<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<name>Beak Mask is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Crowfeather Set.</name>

<description>Wood-carved mask of Eileen the Crow, Hunter of Hunters. The beak contains incense to mask scents of blood and beast." 
Hunters of Hunters dress as crows to suggest sky burial. 
The first Hunter of Hunters came from a foreign land, 
and gave the dead a virtuous native funeral ritual, 
rather than impose a blasphemous Yharnam burial service upon them, 
with the hope that former compatriots might be returned to the skies, 
and find rest in a hunter's dream. "</description>

<location>Bath Messengers in the Hunter's Dream after obtaining the Crow Hunter Badge.</location>

^n"Resembles the mask of a seventeenth century plague doctor. 
Plague doctors also kept aromatic items in the beak of the mask 
as it was thought to ward off infection."

$
<name>Black Church Hat is a Head Armor/Attire in Bloodborne. It is part of the Black Church Set</name>

<description>Attire of Healing Church hunters. 
Most Healing Church hunters are elementary doctors who understand
the importance of early prevention of the scourge, achieved by disposing of victims,
and even potential victims, before signs of sickness manifest themselves. 
Their black attire is synonymous with fear, and that peculiar Yharnam madness."</description>

<location>Buy the Hunter Chief Emblem to gain access to the Grand Cathedral's round plaza in Cathedral Ward. 
That is the locked gate up the stairs past the first Reaper.
From the door, go left, past the enemy with the Flamesprayer, 
and to an alley where several enemies will attack you as you talk to NPCs in windows. 
The Set is in a corpse.</location>

$
<name>Black Hood is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Foreign Set</name>

<description>Hood worn upon awakening to the nightmare of blood and beasts. 
Perhaps its wearer had to stay out of sight, and travel by cover of darkness. 
Without memory. who will ever know?"</description>

<location>Starting equipment</location>

^n"Surprisingly dapper." <!-- Don't hurt me this was on the wiki -->

$
<name>Black Hooded Iron Helm is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of Yahar'Gul Set.</name>

d^"Iron helmet worn by hunters of the Unseen Village. The hunters of Yahar’gul answer 
to the village's founders, the School of Mensis. Hunters in name only, these kidnappers 
wear their black hoods low to shadow their eyes. This helm is made of metal. a rarity 
for hunter garb and has high defence, but only against physical attacks."

L@Yahar'gul, Unseen Village

$
<name>Blindfold Cap is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Choir Set.</name>

<description>Attire of the Choir, high-ranking members of the Healing Church. 
Members of the Choir are both the highest-ranking clerics of the Healing Church,
and scholars who continue the work that began at Byrgenwerth. The eye covering indicates 
their debt to the teachings of Master Willem, even though their paths diverged."</description>

<location>Upper Cathedral Ward</location>

$
<name>Bone Ash Mask is a Head (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Bone Ash Set.</name>

<description>A mask made of bone ash, worn by the oldest keepers. 
The keepers, who mind the slumbering Great Ones, 
gained eternal life, preserved in ashen form in 
a ceremony of flame that cremated body and soul. 
The long, pointed hat is a symbol of the old keepers 
and is considered evidence of their companionship, 
forged in a certain sin."</description>

<location>Can be bought from Insight Bath Messenger in Hunter's Dream after defeating some certain 
bosses in the Chalice Dungeons (Cost: 2 Insights)</location>

$
<name>Brador's Testimony is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. 
It is part of Brador's Set and was added with The Old Hunters DLC.</name>

d^"The scalp of a horrid Cleric Beast, indicating that hunter Brador, 
a Healing Church assassin, had killed a compatriot. Afterward, he 
wore his ally's own scalp, and hid himself away, deep below in a cell. 
The Church provided him with a single, soundless bell of death to 
ensure their secrets would be kept."

<location>Dropped by invading NPC Brador at The Hunter's Nightmare, 
in front of the cell that holds Brador. You may only be invaded here 
after having reached the second lamp of the Fishing Hamlet and talked
to the Harrowed Hunter (or reaching the lamp).</location>

$
<name>Butcher Mask is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the 
Butcher Set. It was added with The Old Hunters DLC.</name>

<description>Mask of the Madaras twins, denizens of the Forbidden Woods, likely 
belonging to the older of the two. The twins grew up in silent kinship 
with a poisonous snake. Eventually they learned human ways, and became hunters. 
When they discovered vermin even in their beloved snake, the younger 
brother is said to have murdered the older."</description>

<location>The Hunter's Nightmare: From the Nightmare Church Lamp run past the one 
Void giant with a cannon and to the right. The path is between the two 
Void Giants. The complete set is there.</location>

$
<name>Crown of Illusions is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>One of the precious secrets of Cainhurst. The old king's crown is said to 
reveal illusions, and expose a mirage that hides a secret. And so Logarius 
donned the crown of his own volition, determined to prevent a single soul from 
stumbling upon the vile secret. What visions did he see, sitting serenely upon his new throne?"</description>

<location>On the Ground after the Martyr Logarius boss fight</location>

^n"Unveils the hidden area behind Logarius' boss room when worn. This leads to a special NPC"

$
<name>Doll Hat is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Doll Set.</name>

<description>A discarded doll hat, likely a spare for dress-up.
A deep love for the doll can be sumised by the fine craftsmanship of this article, 
and the care with which it was kept. It borderlines on mania, and exudes a slight warmth."</description>

<location>Old Abandoned Workshop</location>

$
<name>Enlarged Head is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It was added with The Old Hunters DLC.</name>

<description>An enlarged head of a patient of the Cathedral, with a cavity that just happens 
to fit a human head, although one would be mad to try it on. But if you do, listen 
carefully, for the sticky sound. Drip, drop. As water, seeping up from the depths, slowly, steadily."</description>

<location>Patient Room Floor 5 of the Research Hall surrounded by enlarged head creatures in the left-hand corner.</location>

$
<name>Gehrman's Hunter Cap is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of Gehrman's Hunter Set.</name>

<description>Hunter attire of Gehrman, the first hunter. 
Created before the workshop existed by making adjustments to everyday clothing, and later became 
the basis for all hunter's garb. The hunter's emphasis on engaging beasts with speed, and 
therefore of selecting lightweight attire, no doubt traces back to Gehrman's own combat style."</description>

<location>Obtainable after defeating Gehrman</location>

$
<name>Gold Ardeo is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Executioner Set.</name>

<description>The odd helmet worn by the band of Executioners commanded by the martyr Logarius.
The conical gold helmet, symbol of the executioners, represents luminosity, ambition, and an 
unflagging resolve to face impurity, staring it down with stern golden spirit.
As the great Logarius once said, "Acts of goodness are not always wise, and acts of evil 
are not always foolish, but regardless, we shall always strive to be good."</description>

<location>Purchased from the Messengers</location>

^n"This could be a reference to Pyramid Head from the Silent Hill series, as well as Xanthous Headdress from Dark Souls"

$
<name>Graveguard Mask is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of Graveguard Set.</name>

<description>Mask of Dores, graveguard of the Forbidden Woods. 
His pale countenance mimics the labyrinth watchers. Willem kept two loyal servants back at 
Byrgenwerth. When they were sent into the labyrinth. they encountered the eldritch Truth. and went 
mad. One became the password gatekeeper, while Dores became a graveguard of the forest. 
Both remained loyal, even in madness."</description>

<location>Second half of Forbidden Woods</location>

^n"The mask has similarities to The Mask of the Father from Dark Souls"

$
<name>Grey Wolf Cap is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Ashen Hunter Set.</name>

<description>Attire of the retired hunter Djura. 
This worn wolf cap was his trademark. 
Djura is known through his contact with the Powder Kegs, the heretics of the workshop. He is 
said to have been both uncommonly kind and dreadfully foolish. Djura felt defeated by the state 
of Old Yharnam and renounced his hunter's vows."</description>

<location>Djura's dead body once killed.</location>

^n"The hat's name is a reference to Sif, The Great Grey Wolf from Dark Souls.
This hat hinted that the reason why Djura turned against other hunters is because he's actually 
a pacifist who pities the beasts."

$
<name>Harrowed Hood is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of Harrowed Set and was added with The Old Hunters DLC.</name>

<description>Certain Church hunters obfuscate their identities and slip into the nooks and crannies of the city. 
This is the garb that allows these harrowed individuals to go unnoticed. 
These hunters are keen to early signs of the scourge, serving as a first line of defense against its outbreak. 
Or perhaps, when the time is ripe, they find signs of the scourge where there are none. It just 
goes to show, the corner beggar is not always who he seems."</description>

<location>From the Fishing Hamlet first lantern, take the shortcut ladder up and immediately to your right 
will be a second floor opening into a shanty shack. It is being guarded by two enemies and is at 
the end of the room. (Note: you will need to have kicked down the shortcut ladder)</location>

^n"It is suggested the Beggar could be one of those Harrowed Church Hunters. Based on item description, the Harrowed hunters would blend into society and kill people who were 
suspected to soon turn into beasts. Assassins similar to Brador, except they targeted normal folk, 
usually before they turned. The beggar look possibly means they killed victims in dark alleys and hid bodies.
The last line, finding signs of the scourge where there are none suggests that this got out of hand. 
The suspicious beggar, possible harrowed hunter eventually lost it as he became a beast and 
probably simply began killing people, regardless of whether they were infected or not."

$
<name>Henryk's Hunter Cap is a Head Armor/Attire in Bloodborne. It is part of Henryk's Hunter Set. </name>

<description>Hunter's hat worn by Henryk, the old hunter. 
The taciturn old hunter Henryk was once partners with Father Gascoigne, and though they were 
a fierce and gallant duo, their partnership led to Henryk's tragically long life. 
Henryk's unique yellow garb is resistant to bolt and will be of great help to any hunter who 
has inherited the onus of the hunt." </description>

<location>It can be acquired by defeating Henryk in the Tomb of Oedon.and then purchasing it from the Insight Messengers for 1 Insight.
In order for him to appear there, you must speak with Eileen the Crow and defeat Vicar Amelia.</location>

$
<name>Hunter Hat is a Head Armor/Attire in Bloodborne. It is part of the Hunter Set. </name>

<description>One of the standard articles of hunter attire fashioned at the workshop. 
A fine piece of hunter attire that provides stable defence to anyone facing Yharnam's beastly threat. 
Recognizable by its withered feathers, this cap is fashioned after one of the old hunters.</description>

<location>Purchased from Messengers or found in the sewers in Central Yharnam</location>

$
<name>Iron Yahar'gul Helm is a Head Armor/Attire in Bloodborne. It is part of Yahar'gul Set.</name>

<description>Iron helmet worn by hunters of the Unseen Village. 
Removing the hood reveals something reminiscent of a warrior of a previous age. 
This headwear is made of metal, a rarity for hunter garb, and has high defense, but only against 
physical attacks."</description>

<location>Yahar'Gul, Unseen Village</location>

$
<name>Knight's Wig is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Knight's Set.</name>

<description>Adornment prized by the knights of Cainhurst. 
Resembles a ponytail of silver hair. 
The Cainhurst way is a mix of nostalgia and bombast. They take great pride even in the blood-stained 
corpses of beasts that they leave behind, confident that they will stand as examples of decadent art."</description>

<location>rooftop of Cainhurst library</location>

$
<name>Madman Hood is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Madman Set.</name>

<description>Most tomb prospectors, members of the Healing Church chosen to explore the old labyrinth, are unable 
to withstand the weight of the old knowledge, and go mad. This attire is worn by those lost souls. 
Truth oft resembles madness, inaccessible to the dull of mind. Those who go mad are merely thoughtful 
souls who failed to reach any conclusions."</description>

<location>Lower Hintertomb Chalice Dungeon</location>

$
<name>Maria Hunter Cap is a Head Armor/Attire in Bloodborne. It is part of Maria Hunter Set, and was added with The Old Hunters DLC.</name>

<description>Among the first hunters, all students of Gehrman, was the lady hunter Maria. This was her hunter's cap,
crafted in Cainhurst. Maria is distantly related to the undead queen, but had great admiration for 
Gehrman, unaware of his curious mania"</description>

<location>Purchase from Insight Messengers for 3 Insight after defeating Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower</location>

$
<name>Master's Iron Helm is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>An iron helm resembling an upside-down bucket. 
A single hole allows one to peek out with a single eye, which is probably all that its original 
owner had. The iron helm is passed down among masters of the League. Valtr had in fact lost the ability 
to see Vermin long ago."</description>

<location>Dropped by Valtr, the leader of The League after consuming 5 Vermin and speaking with him. Reloading 
the area in any way causes Valtr to disappear, leaving behind the helm in his place.</location>

^n"Fairly similar to the helmet used by Ned Kelly, an Australian outlaw from the 19 century.
If you summon Valtr after acquiring this helm, he will not be wearing it."

$
<name>Mensis Cage is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>The School of Mensis controls the Unseen Village. This hexagonal iron cage suggests their strange ways. 
The cage is a device that restrains the will of the self, allowing one to see the profane world for 
what it is. It also serves as an antenna that facilitates contact with the Great Ones of the dream.
But to an observer, the iron cage appears to be precisely what delivered them to their harrowing nightmare."</description>

^n""Mensis" is a Latin word for "month", possibly deriving from a proto-indo-european word for "moon, measure",
as referring to the moons phases as a measure of time. "Menses", or "months" is also the origin of the word 
"menstruation", which was once associated with the phases of the moon. "Mensis" is the genitive form of 
"mens", the Latin word for "mind" or "thought". The particular case translates as "of the mind" or "mind's".
(Possibly a wordplay on both?)"

$
<name>Old Hunter Cap is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of Old Hunter Set and was added with The 
Old Hunters expansion.</name>

<description>Old Hunter Cap with a wide brim that hides their sharp gaze 
In the old days, when hunters were ten a penny, this was their standard garb."</description>

<location>The Hunter's Nightmare</location>

$
<name>One-Eyed Iron Helm is a Head Armor/Attire in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>An iron helm resembling an upside-down bucket. A single hole allows one to peek out with a single
eye, which is probably all that its original owner had."</description>

<location>Dropped by killing Valtr, the leader of The League.</location>

$
<name>Rumpled Yharnam Hat is a Head Armor/Attire in Bloodborne. It is part of the Shabby Set.</name>

<description>Common Yharnam cap. Well-worn and losing it's shape."</description>

<location>Old Yharnam</location>

$
<name>Tomb Prospector Hood is a Head Armor/Attire in Bloodborne. It is part of Tomb Prospector Set.</name>

<description>Attire of tomb prospectors who explore the old labyrinth on behalf of the Healing Church. 
The Healing Church traces its roots to Byrgenwerth, and is therefore aware of the ruins' true importance. 
They contain much more than mere hunter trinkets, indeed, they hide the very secrets of the old Great Ones. 
sought after by those with the insight to imagine greatness."</description>

<location>Purchased from Messengers after receiving Radiant Sword Hunter Badge</location>

$
<name>Top Hat is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>Hat worn by Hunters who admire formality: Some hunters place an emphasis on form, as seen by the use of the 
threaded cane. For them, formality, beauty, and justice are the very essence of our humanity, and precisely 
what keeps hunters from becoming something else."</description>

<location>Found directly left of the Cathedral Ward lamp in a circular courtyard on a body hidden behind some gravestones</location>

$
<name>White Church Hat is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of White Church Set.</name>

<description>Attire of special Church doctors. 
These doctors are superiors to the black preventative hunters, and specialists in experimentally-backed blood 
ministration and the scourge of the beast. They believe that medicine is not a means of treatment but rather 
a method for research. and that some knowledge can only be obtained by exposing oneself to sickness."</description>

<location>Forbidden Woods</location>

$
<name>Yamamura Hunter Hat is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Yamamura Set. It was was added 
with The Old Hunters DLC.</name>

<description>A standard hunter's hat, worn by Yamamura the Wanderer." 
"This hat and staff were given to him when he became a hunter and confederate of the League."</description>

<location>Can be obtained by killing Old Hunter Yamamura after opening his cell with the Underground Cell Key from the 
Research Hall. Other methods of obtaining it need testing.</location>

$
<name>Yharnam Hunter Cap is a Head Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Yharnam Hunter Set.</name>

<description>Ludwig, the first hunter of the Healing Church, once recruited Yharnamites to serve as hunters. 
This hunter's attire was made for new recruits, and has excellent straightforward defense. 
But not nearly enough to allow an ordinary man to stand any real chance against the beasts"</description>

<location>Purchase from the Messengers at Hunter's Dream from the start of the game. Each piece costs 500 Blood Echoes</location>

<!-- Chest -->

$
<name>Ashen Hunter Garb is a Chest Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of Ashen Hunter Set.</name>

<description>Attire of the retired hunter Djura. 
Painted with ash in a ceremony to ward off blood. 
Djura is known through his contact with the Powder Kegs, the heretics of the workshop. He is said to have been
both uncommonly kind and dreadfully foolish. Djura felt defeated by the state of Old Yharnam, and renounced 
his hunter's vows."</description>

<location>Djura's dead body once killed. If body is unreachable, reload Old Yharnam, and climb back up to his gatling gun.</location>

^n"The garb piece has the highest Beasthood, surpassing Bardor's Set."

$
<name>Beast Hide Garb is a Chest Armor/Attire in Bloodborne. It is part of Brador's Set and was added with The Old Hunters DLC.</name>

<description>The bloodied hide of a horrible Cleric Beast, pulled over the back. Without the attacked beast hide this foreigner garb 
wouldn't raise anyone's eyebrows. Brador donned a compatriot's beastly scalp and hide while still moist with blood. 
Most of the blood stains on this hide were from that day"</description>

<location>Fishing Hamlet, you must defeat Brador in a specific location.</location>

$
<name>Black Church Garb is a Chest Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Black Church Set</name>

<description>Attire of Healing Church hunters. The Holy Shawl, symbol of the Healing Church, flutters proudly on their backs. 
Most Healing Church hunters are elementary doctors who understand the importance of early prevention of the scourge, 
achieved by disposing of victims, and even potential victims, before signs of sickness manifest themselves. 
Their black attire is synonymous with fear, and that peculiar Yharnam madness"</description>

<location>Cathedral Ward</location>

$
<name>Butcher Garb is a Chest Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Butcher Set. This was added with The Old Hunters DLC.</name>

<description>Garb of the Madaras twins, denizens of the Forbidden Woods, likely belonging to the older of the two. 
Both the twins became hunters, and brought back and dissected their beast prey, in order to support the villagers in their 
forbidden research."</description>

<location>The Hunter's Nightmare</location>

$
<name>Bone Ash Armor is a Chest Armor/Attire in Bloodborne. It is part of the Bone Ash Set.</name>

<description>Armor made of bone ash,worn by the oldest keepers. 
The keepers, who mind the slumbering Great Ones, 
gained eternal life, preserved in ashen form in 
a ceremony of flame that cremated body and soul 
Now, their frail armor is white and sinewy, 
a window into an arcane lost art."</description>

<location>Central Pthumerian Labyrinth (Layer Two Boss)</location>

$
<name>Cainhurst Armor is a Chest Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Cainhurst Set.</name>

<description>Silver armor worn by the royal guards who protect Annalise, Queen of the Vilebloods at Cainhurst Castle. 
This paper-thin silver armor is said to deflect blood of ill-intent, and is what allows the royal guards to capture prey for 
their beloved Queen, so that one day, she may bear a Child of Blood."</description>

<location>Can be purchased from the messengers for 44,000 blood echoes after obtaining the Cainhurst badge from Annalise, Queen of the Vilebloods.</location>

^n"In the Cainhurst dining room you can find a portrait of a young man wearing Cainhurst Armor.

$
<name>Charred Hunter Garb is a Chest Armor/Attire in Bloodborne. It is part of the Charred Hunter Set.</name>

<description>One of the staple articles of hunter attire, fashioned at the workshop. A product of the scourge of the beast 
that once plagued Old Yharnam and culminated in the town's fiery cleansing. The cape's dampness makes it 
highly resistant to fire. Wearers of this attire hunted down Victims of the scourge who survived the raging 
flames and stench of singed blood."</description>

<location>Old Yharnam</location>

$
<name> Choir Garb</name>

<description> Attire of the Choir, high-ranking members of the Healing Church. 
Members of the Choir are both the highest-ranking clerics of the Healing Church, and scholars who continue the work that began at Byrgenwerth. 
Together with the left behind Great One, they look to the skies, in search of astral signs, that may lead them to the rediscovery of true greatness."</description>

<location> Upper Cathedral Ward</location>

$
<name> Constable's Garb</name>

<description> Once upon a time a troupe of foreign constables chased a beast all the way to Yahrnam, and this is what they wore. 
The constables became victims of the beast, except for one survivor, who in turn devoured the creature whole, all by himself. 
The fable is a favorite among Yahrnamites, who are partial to any stories of pompous, intolerant foreigners, who suffer for their ignorance. It makes the blood taste that much sweeter."</description>

<location> The Hunter's Nightmare: Near the bridge over the blood river with the Bloodlicker enemies, find a Beast Cutter hunter NPC and defeat him. Climb up the ladder, drop down to the next platform and walk across the wooden beams to a body holding the armor.</location>

^n" The set, minus the helmet, is reminiscent of a Civil War Union general's outfit.

$
<name> Crowfeather</name>

<description> Wood-carved mask/Attire of Eileen the Crow, Hunter of Hunters. The beak contains incense to mask scents of blood and beast. 
Hunters of Hunters dress as crows to suggest sky burial. The first Hunter of Hunters came from a foreign land, and gave the dead a virtuous native funeral ritual, rather than impose a blasphemous Yharnam burial service upon them. with the hope that former compatriots might be returned to the skies, and find rest in the Hunter's Dream"</description>

<location> Bought from Messengers after receiving the Crow Hunter Badge from Eileen the Crow by finishing her quests or killing her.</location>

^n" Has good physical defense and blood defense.
This set's headpiece Beak Mask notably has the highest frenzy resistance, the rest are surpassed by Ashen Hunter Set.
Prior to patch 1.04, the male version of the chest piece had a bug causing the right side of the cape to be abnormally stretchy. This bug was not present on the female set.

$
<name> Decorative Old Hunter Garb</name>

<description> Old Hunter Garb decorated with brass trinkets 
At the time, some hunters believed that certain metals would ward off beast blood. 
On a night of the hunt, it is no wonder that people would resort to superstition."</description>

<location> Abandoned Workshop</location>

$
<name> Doll Clothes</name>

<description> Discarded doll clothing, likely a spare for dress-up." 
" A deep love for the doll can be surmised by the fine craftsmanship of this article, and the care with which it was kept." 
" It borderlines on mania, and exudes a slight warmth."</description>

<location> Abandoned Workshop</location>

$
<name> Decorative Old Hunter Garb</name>

<description> Old Hunter Garb decorated with brass trinkets 
At the time, some hunters believed that certain metals would ward off beast blood. 
On a night of the hunt, it is no wonder that people would resort to superstition."</description>

<location> Research Hall</location>

$
<name> Enlarged Head</name>

<description> An enlarged head of a patient of the Cathedral, with a cavity that just happens to fit a human head, although one would be mad to try it on. 
But if you do, listen carefully, for the sticky sound. Drip, drop. As water, seeping up from the depths, slowly, steadily."</description>

<location> Patient Room Floor 5 of the Research Hall surrounded by enlarged head creatures in the left-hand corner.</location>

^n" Good armor to use against the Living Failures.
Lore theories can be found under Blood Lore.

$
<name> Executioner Garb</name>

<description>  Attire worn by the band of executioners commanded by the martyr Logarius. 
Later became the basis for all Church attire, with its heavy draping of Holy Shawl. 
As the great Logarius once said, "Acts of goodness are not always wise, and acts of evil are not always foolish, but regardless, we shall always strive to be good."</description>

<location> Cainhurst Castle, after first encountering the gargoyles, to the right of the entrance to the first library. Found on a body guarded by two gargoyles</location>

$
<name> Foreign Garb</name>

<description> Clothing worn upon awakening to the nightmare of blood and beasts. 
Not typical clothing for Yharnam, perhaps it is of foreign origin. It is said, after all, the traveler came to Yharnam from afar. 
Without memory, who will ever know?"</description>

<location> Starting equipment</location>

$
<name> Gasgoigne's Garb</name>

<description> Hunter attire worn by Father Gascoigne. 
The dingy scarf is a Holy Shawl and symbol of 
the Healing Church, from which Gascoigne would 
eventually part ways. 
"Father" is a title used for clerics in a foreign land, 
and there is no such rank in the Healing Church."</description>

<location> Can be bought with insight from the messengers in the Hunters Dream.</location>

$
<name> Graveguard Robe</name>

<description> Robe of Dores, graveguard of the Forbidden Woods. 
His pale countenance mimics the labyrinth watchers. Willem kept two loyal servants back at Byrgenwerth. When they were sent into the labyrinth. they encountered the eldritch Truth. and went mad. One became the password gatekeeper, while Dores became a graveguard of the forest. 
Both remained loyal, even in madness."</description>

<location> Forbidden Woods</location>

$
<name> Harrowed Garb</name>

<description> Certain Church hunters obfuscate their identities and slip into the nooks and crannies of the city. 
This is the garb that allows these harrowed individuals to go unnoticed. 
These hunters are keen to early signs of the scourge, serving as a first line of defense against its outbreak. 
Or perhaps, when the time is ripe, they find signs of the scourge where there are none. It just goes to show, the corner beggar is not always who he seems."</description>

<<<<<<< HEAD
<location> From the Fishing Hamlet first lantern, take the shortcut ladder up and immediately to your right will be a second floor opening into a shanty shack. It is being guarded by two enemies and is at the end of the room. (Note: you will need to have kicked down the shortcut ladder)</location>

$
<name> Henryk's Hunter Garb</name>

<description> Hunter's attire worn by Henryk, the old hunter. 
The taciturn old hunter Henryk was once partners with Father Gascoigne, and though they were a fierce and gallant duo, their partnership led to Henryk's tragically long life. 
Henryk's unique yellow garb is resistant to bolt and will be of great help to any hunter who has inherited the onus of the hunt."</description>

<location> It can be acquired by defeating Henryk in the Tomb of Oedon.and then purchasing it from the Insight Messengers for 3 Insight.
In order for him to appear there, you must speak with Eileen the Crow in Central Yharnam and open the gate in Cathedral Ward using the Hunter Chief Emblem.</location>

$
<name> Hunter Garb</name>

<description> "One of the standard articles of hunter attire fashioned at the workshop, this one without the cape that wipes away blood. 
A fine piece of hunter attire that provides stable defence to anyone facing Yharnam's beastly threat.
Allows one to stalk beasts unannounced, by cover of night." </description>

<location> Hunter Garb with cape found at the end of the sewers of Central Yharnam beside an enemy along with the rest of the Hunter Set (A)
Hunter Garb without cape found directly left of the Cathedral Ward Lamp in a circular courtyard behind some gravestones along with the rest of the Hunter Set (B)</location>

$
<name> Knight's Set</name>

<description> Adornment prized by the knights of Cainhurst. Resembles a ponytail of silver hair. 
The Cainhurst way is a mix of nostalgia and bombast. They take great pride even in the blood-stained corpses of beasts that they leave behind. confident that they will stand as examples of decadent art." 
"Attire/Gloves of the knights of Cainhurst. A regal piece graced by intricate goldwork. 
The Cainhurst way is a mix of nostalgia and bombast. 
They take great pride even in the blood-stained corpses of beasts that they leave behind. confident that they will stand as examples of decadent art."</description>

<location> Forsaken Cainhurst Castle - The Wig can be found on the roof before the boss. The rest of the set is in the hidden section of the library in a chest. To access this area you have to go to the second floor of the library and through the open window jump down the ledges until you find yourself on the balcony, from there enter a room which contains the chest with the remainder of the set.</location>

^n" The knight set changes its look depending on the gender of your character.
There's actually a small dagger on your character's back when you equip these clothes.
Relevant lore theories can be found under The Mysteries of Cainhurst Garb & Architecture.

$
<name> Madman Garb</name>

<description> Most tomb prospectors, members of the Healing Church chosen to explore the old labyrinth, are unable to withstand the weight of the old knowledge, and go mad. 
This attire is worn by those lost souls. 
The appendages draped across them are said to be a kind of protective charm, or at least, that is what these lost souls believe with all their hearts."</description>

<location> Chalice Dungeon</location>

$
<name> Maeia Hunter Garb</name>

<description> Among the first hunters, all students of Gehrman, was the lady hunter Maria. This was her hunter's Garb, crafted in Cainhurst. 
Maria is distantly related to the undead queen, but had great admiration for Gehrman, unaware of his curious mania"</description>

<location> Purchase from Insight Messengers for 5 Insight after defeating Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower</location>

$
<name> Noble Dress</name>

<description> A finely tailored bordeaux dress. 
Worn by the nobles of the old bloodline that traces back to the forsaken Castle Cainhurst."</description>

<location> Chest at cainhurst castle behind the first door up the stairs to the left next to the tables</location>

^n" Before update it was called the "Alluring Dress"
Relevant lore theories exist under The Mysteries of Cainhurst Garb and Architecture.

$
<name> Sweaty Clothes</name>

<description> Common Yharnam clothing. 
Well-worn and damp with sweat."</description>

<location> Old Yharnam</location>

$
<name> Student Unifrom</name>

<description> Uniform of the students of Byrgenwerth, a bygone institute of learning. Features a thick cape. 
The Healing Church has its roots in Byrgenwerth, and naturally borrows heavily from its uniform design. 
The focus not on knowledge. or thought. but on pure pretension would surely bring Master Willem to despair, if only he knew."</description>

<location> Byrgenwerth and Lecture Building</location>

$
<name> Tomb Prospector Garb</name>

<description> Attire of tomb prospectors who explore the old labyrinth on behalf of the Healing Church. 
The Healing Church traces its roots to Byrgenwerth, and is therefore aware of the ruins' true importance. 
They contain much more than mere hunter trinkets, indeed, they hide the very secrets of the old Great Ones. sought after by those with the insight to imagine greatness."</description>

<location> Can be purchased from Messengers in Hunter's Dream</location>

$
<name> White Chruch Garb</name>

<description> Attire of special Church doctors. 
These doctors are superiors to the black preventative hunters, and specialists in experimentally-backed blood ministration and the scourge of the beast. 
They believe medicine is not a means of treatment but rather a method for research. and some knowledge can only be obtained by exposing oneself to sickness."</description>

$
<name> Khaki Haori</name>

<description> Garb of a distant Eastern land, worn by Yamamura the Wanderer. 
This Eastern warrior pursued a beast for honourable revenge, then became a hunter of the League. But when he stared straight into impurity, it drove him mad."</description>

<location> Can be obtained by killing Old Hunter Yamamura after opening his cell with the Underground Cell Key from the Research Hall. Other methods of obtaining it need testing.</location>

$
<name> Yahar'gul Black Garb</name>

<description> Thick black pullover worn by hunters of the Unseen Village. 
The hunters of Yahar'gul answer to the village's founders, the School of Mensis. Hunters in name only, these kidnappers blend into the night wearing this attire. 
Designed primarily to defend from physical attacks, the binding of thick rope serves both to protect its wearer, and restrain his foes."</description>

<location> Yahar'gul Set</location>

$
<name> Yharnam Hunter Garb</name>

<description> Ludwig, the first hunter of the Healing Church, once recruited Yharnamites to serve as hunters. 
This hunter's attire was made for new recruits, and has excellent straightforward defense. 
But not nearly enough to allow an ordinary man to stand any real chance against the beasts."</description>

<!-- gloves -->
$
H@ 
=======
L@Old Yharnam

$
H@Choir Garb is a Chest Armor/Attire in Bloodborne. It is part of Choir Set.

d^"Attire of the Choir, high-ranking members of the Healing Church. 
Members of the Choir are both the highest-ranking clerics of the Healing Church, and scholars who continue the 
work that began at Byrgenwerth. Together with the left behind Great One, they look to the skies, in search of 
astral signs, that may lead them to the rediscovery of true greatness."

L@Upper Cathedral Ward

$
H@Constable's Garb is a Chest Armor (Attire) in Bloodborne. It is part of the Constable Set and was added with The Old Hunters DLC.

d^"Once upon a time a troupe of foreign constables chased a beast all the way to Yahrnam, and this is what they wore. 
The constables became victims of the beast, except for one survivor, who in turn devoured the creature whole, all by himself. 
The fable is a favorite among Yahrnamites, who are partial to any stories of pompous, intolerant foreigners, who 
suffer for their ignorance. It makes the blood taste that much sweeter."

L@The Hunter's Nightmare

^n"The set, minus the helmet, is reminiscent of a Civil War Union general's outfit."

$
>>>>>>> 71a56472d7e93d8be40334299e1f63d11195be36
