<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!-- Bosses, "</boss><boss>" denotes the beginning of an entry.-->

<?xml-model href="../RNC/mainSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<lore>
<equipment></equipment>
<area></area>
<npc>
    <name></name>
    <description></description>
    <notes></notes>
    <location></location>
</npc>


<boss>
<name>Blood-Starved Beast (血に渇いた獣 Chi ni kawaita kemono lit. "Blood-thirsty Beast"), also known as the Thirsty Beast, is an optional boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>This malformed beast has had all of the skin peeled off its back, making for a truly gruesome sight. Capable of extremely quick and agile attacks, this erratic and unpredictable enemy is a truly formidable foe, whether you choose to face it alone or with other Hunters at your side.    </description>

<notes>This boss fight is optional, but it is necessary if you wish to do any of the Pthumeru Chalices, Hintertomb Chalices or accessing Hypogean Gaol for befriending Djura.
In the church after Djura in Old Yharnam, there is a crucified Blood-Starved Beast hanging in the center of the room.
The Beast Patients beneath this corpse have formed a circle around her and they are chanting.
On the altar several gold embossments depict The Moon Presence. It is of course concealed and you'll have to look closely.
The limbs of Blood-starved Beast very much resemble the tails of The Moon Presence.
When she perform her "poison explosion" she can mimic the form of Manus' horns with her flaps.</notes>

<location place="Old Yharnam">Old Yharnam in a ruined church at the bottom of the area.
Hintertomb Chalice (Final Boss)
Ailing Loran Chalice (Layer 2 Boss)
Hunter's Nightmare (DLC), in a cave with the Gatling Gun hunter</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Cleric Beast (聖職者の獣 Seishoku-sha no kemono lit. "Cleric Beast") is a Boss in Bloodborne. While optional, it's likely the first boss that most new players encounter.</name>

<description>The Cleric Beast is an enormous creature with disfigured horns. With high agility and superhuman strength, this boss should not be taken lightly.
This creature owes its name to a rumor which states that members of the Healing Church would eventually transform into the most hideous beasts.</description>

<notes>The Cleric Beast's design appears to be inspired by the legend of a supernatural creature known as a "wendigo."
The legend of the wendigo states that it grew in size depending on how many humans it had eaten. Since Brador wears the skin of a Cleric Beast, yet it's small enough for Brador to comfortably wear as clothing, that might mean that Cleric Beasts start off small at first. Even more chilling, if this is true, that means this particular Cleric Beast you fight on the Great Bridge has eaten many humans and thus grew to an enormous size.
Its horns, which are very misshapen, are a trademark of this particular creature.
The music score of the Cleric Beast fight is the same as the one used for the "Project Beast" trailer, albeit with minor modifications.
At the beginning of the game, when you climb the ladder that leads to Gilbert, you hear an unknown creature screeching loudly throughout the city. This is a foreshadow to new players, warning them of terrible things that lurk in the city. In this case, the loud screech belongs to the Cleric Beast, who continues to screech loudly while it tries to kill you.
The Cleric Beast shares similar characteristics to Manus, Father of the Abyss from Dark Souls; they both have red eyes on their horns and their left arm is larger than their right.
The fur on his legs looks unusually like fungus and there are nails jammed into his legs.</notes>

<location place="Central Yharnam">Central Yharnam at the far end of the great bridge.</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Darkbeast Paarl (黒獣パール Kokujū Pāru lit. "Black Beast Paarl" ) is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>A malformed beast enveloped in blue lightning. With a long body made of only bones, and a wrinkle-covered skull, people say this beast must be very old, very ancient. Or perhaps, it is a descendant of the city of the plague of beasts.</description>

<notes>Archibald was fond of the sparks emitted from the Darkbeast, and so he created Tonitrus and Bolt Paper to replicate the sparks.
Paarl is Afrikaans for "pearl", paarl is based on the Dutch word for pearl, "parel".
If you've fought him at least once before you can find Paarl poised, looking at the nightmare gate like a cat ready to pounce. Paarl is also wagging his tail and making growling noises that sound a lot like that of a lion.
While casting his electric explosion Paarl curves his long neck all the way down then swings it back across his back. The animation is so dramatic that it would cause whiplash in any real living animal.</notes>

<location place="Yahar'gul Unseen_Village">Hypogean Gaol</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Father Gascoigne (ガスコイン神父 Gasukoin shinpu lit. "Father Gascoigne") is a Boss in Bloodborne;</name>

<description>In beast form, he becomes stronger, faster and more aggressive, at the cost of his sanity. However, later in the game, multiple details come to light that some beasts, perhaps even all, still have a conscience, meaning their humanity isn't completely gone.
It's possible to use the Tiny Music Box to stun Gascoigne, but mind that can't interrupt his combos this way, and on the third stun he will assume Beast Form regardless of health. In Beast Form, you will be able to stun him one last time before this strategy stops working altogether.
His equipment set reveals that his clothing had a "pungent beastly smell," indicating that his transformation had been slow and ate away at his humanity over time.
Even though his equipment set is actually above-average when dealing with fire damage, Father Gascoigne is still weak against fire damage.
This is an indicator of just how far the beast plague has taken its toll on Father Gascoigne; he's become more beast-like over time.</description>

<notes>In the Alpha version, he muttered "Umbasa" upon killing the player, a reference to one of From Software's games, "Demon's Souls".
If you summon Father Gascoigne for the Cleric Beast boss fight and you happen to have the Tiny Music Box, using it will make Father Gascoigne give you an unimpressed grunt or a small chuckle.
Gascoigne's surname is based off Irish origin. His dialogue, "beasts all over the shop" is also based off from an Irish colloquialism.
As his attire description reveals, the title "Father" is actually a reference to his literal paternal status: he has 2 daughters, both of which still hope for his return after the hunt. 
However, it could also point to Gascoigne's Irish connections, as priests in Ireland are colloquially referred to as "Father", think calling someone "Sir".
Also, Gascoigne can use his firearm even while his axe is transformed.
Normally players cannot use firearms when the Hunter Axe is transformed, giving Gascoigne a unique characteristic amongst many Hunters and Old Hunters.
Father Gascoine hates the sewers. If you have summoned him for the fight against the Cleric Beast, any attempts to lead him near the sewers will result in him using his Silencing Blank and leaving. Effectively wasting your Insight.</notes>

<location place="Central Yharnam">Father Gascoigne can be found at the end of Central Yharnam.</location>

<dialogue><line>During the intro 
"...Beasts all over the shop... You'll be one of them, sooner or later..." </line>

<line>Upon killing the player 
"Too Proud to show your true face eh? But what a sporting hunt, it was!" </line>

<line>When entering phase 2 (and only the first time you enter phase 2) 
"What's that smell? ... The sweet blood, oh, it sings to me. It's enough to make a man sick"</line></dialogue>

</boss><boss>
<name>Gehrman, the First Hunter (最初の狩人ゲールマン Saisho no kariudo Gēruman lit. "Gehrman, the First Hunter") is a Boss in Bloodborne, and one of the three possible final bosses of the game. </name>

<description>"Hm hm hm ha ha ha... Dear oh dear, what was it? The Hunt? The Blood? Or the horrible Dream? Oh, it doesn't matter... It always comes down to the hunters' helper to clean up after these sort of messes." 
"Tonight... Gehrman joins the hunt...."</description>

<notes>When killed, Gehrman raises his arms in an almost perfect "make contact" gesture, before falling to his knees, looking to his hands and then falling forward. It should also be noted that Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower shares this same action upon death (with the exception of groaning rather than speaking final words).</notes>

<location place="Hunter's Dream">Hunter's Dream</location>

<dialogue>
    <line>See Gehrman's NPC page.</line>
</dialogue>

</boss><boss>
<name>Micolash, Host of the Nightmare (悪夢の主ミコラーシュ Akumu no shu Mikorāshu lit. "Micolash, Lord of the Nightmare") is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>"Ahhh Kos... or some say Kosm.  Do you hear our prayers?" </description>

<notes>The body found after defeating The One Reborn (Advent Plaza at end of Yahar'gul) wears a Mensis Cage just like that of Micolash.  It is also the portal by which the Hunter enters the Lecture Hall 2nd Floor which leads to Nightmare of Mensis.  Given that Micolash is the "Host of the Nightmare", it is likely that this corpse is his actual body in the waking world.</notes>

<location place="Nightmare Of Mensis">Nightmare of Mensis</location>

<dialogue><line>Ahh, Kos, or some say Kosm... Do you hear our prayers?"</line>

<line>"No, we shall not abandon the dream."</line>

<line>No one can catch us! No one can stop us now! [cackling]."</line>

<line>Ah hah hah ha! Ooh! Majestic! A hunter is a hunter, even in a dream. But, alas, not too fast! The nightmare swirls and churns unending!"</line>

<line>As you once did for the vacuous Rom, grant us eyes, grant us eyes. Plant eyes on our brains, to cleanse our beastly idiocy."</line>

<line>The grand lake of mud, hidden now, from sight."</line>

<line>The cosmos, of course!"</line>

<line>Let us sit about, and speak feverishly. Chatting into the wee hours of..."</line>

<line>New ideas, of the higher plane!"</line>

<line>Now I'm waking up, I'll forget everything..."</line>
</dialogue>

</boss><boss>
<name>Martyr Logarius (殉教者ローゲリウス Junkyōsha Rōgeriusu lit. "Martyr Logarius") is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>"Acts of goodness are not always wise, and acts of evil are not always foolish, but regardless, we shall always strive to be good".
When asked about the Vilebloods, Alfred offers some insight on Logarius. According to him, Master Logarius led the Executioners in a charge against the Vilebloods at Castle Cainhurst. Alfred implies that Logarius stayed behind while the rest of the Executioners escaped.</description>

<notes>His sword is very similar in design to the Soulbrandt, a blade from Demon's Souls.
His scythe on the other hand is a replica of the one conjured by Pthumerian Elder.
Logarius is likely connected to the The Emperor Tarot Card.
The Sword of Logarius  much resembles The Drake Sword from DS1 . 
Like The Drake Sword it is very broad at the hilt and the edge is slightly curved, like a flamberge. The colors are different.
The sword that Logarius uses is a kris, an Indonesian sword with unusual curves.</notes>

<location place="Forsaken Castle Cainhurst">Forsaken Cainhurst Castle</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>The One Reborn (再誕者 Saitansha lit. "The One Reborn") is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>A being reborn, as part of the Mensis Ritual, The One Reborn is a colossal undead mass. He is assisted by red Chime Maidens (killable).</description>

<notes>The arena of this boss and the placement of the Chime Maidens is reminiscent of the Tower Knight and the archers in Demon's Souls; furthermore, Tower Knight's weak spot is his legs while this boss is entirely constructed from leg parts.
The One Reborn resembles Nito from Dark Souls and Dark Souls II's The Rotten. Undead amalgams first appeared in Demons' Souls.</notes>

<location place="Yahar'gul Unseen Village">Advent Plaza</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Shadow of Yharnam (ヤーナムの影 Yānamu no kage lit. "Shadow of Yharnam") is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>The Shadow of Yharnam consists of three figures shrouded in black robes. As the fight progresses they are revealed to have been infected with the parasitic snakes that infest the woods and undergo gruesome mutations. They share a symbiotic link with the vipers, either transforming their arms to use them as whips or summoning gigantic serpents to devour victims.They are servants of Queen Yharnam, as their name implies. </description>

<location place="Forbidden Woods">At the very end/bottom of the Forbidden Woods.
As regular enemies at Mergo's Loft Middle.</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Vicar Amelia (教区長エミーリア Kyōku-chō Emīria lit. "Vicar Amelia/Emilia") is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>Vicars were the heads of the Healing Church, as is revealed in the item description for the Gold Pendant, which she can be seen clutching in the cutscene, and even in battle after her grotesque transformation. This would make her the last Vicar, who oversaw the Church as Yharnam fell to the beasthood brought upon it by misuse of the Old Blood. As the player finds her, she is seen praying to the altar in the Grand Cathedral which hold a misshapen skull, presumably that of Laurence, the founder of the Healing Church. Here she kneels awaiting her inevitable transformation, praying, clasping her pendant which existed to carry a reminder that had been all but forgotten, and that may have prevented the madness that led Yharnam to ruin before her eyes: Fear the Old Blood.</description>

<notes>After defeating her and interacting with the altar, it will be night time.
Her dialogues can be heard before triggering the fight if the player stands at the top of the stairs and listens closely.
Vicar Amelia shares her boss theme with the Cleric Beast, presumably because both Amelia and the Cleric Beast were once members of clergy and got turned into beasts.
Intrestingly enough, Vicar Amelia also makes a re-appearance in the Old Hunter's DLC as a Church Hunter.  She is wearing the white garbed Church hunter by the Surgery Alter after you defeat Ludwig the Accursed, while also chanting the same chant when you first encounter her in the Grand Cathedral.  Becareful when you approach her, as another Church Hunter is hiding and waiting to ambush.</notes>

<location place="Cathedral Ward">In Cathedral Ward, inside the Grand Cathedral.</location>

<dialogue>
<line>Remain wary of the frailty of men. Their wills are weak, minds young.
Were it not for fear, death would go unlamented.
Seek the old blood.
Let us pray, let us wish... to partake in communion.
Let us partake in communion... and feast upon the old blood.
Our thirst for blood satiates us, soothes our fears.
Seek the old blood.
But beware the frailty of men. Their wills are weak, minds young.
The foul beasts will dangle nectar and lure the meek into the depths."
Remain wary of the frailty of men..."</line>
</dialogue>

</boss><boss>
<name>Witch of Hemwick (ヘムウィックの魔女 Hemuuikku no majo lit. "Witch of Hemwick") is a Boss in Bloodborne. It is a special variation of the Eye Collector. </name>

<description>'In the outskirts of Yharnam, the city of gravekeeper witches carved by the sunlight, Hemwick. In its depths, an old, gigantic structure and one Old lady lies in wait. Holding suspicious rituals in the deepest of the night, for that very purpose it is said that she gathers the eyeballs of the living. In the city where unwanted corpses would be gathered and disposed of, her outfit might just be befitting of one such place.</description>

<notes>Despite the boss's name, there are actually two witches, which are visually identical.
She propably comes from the Unseen Village as a few of her kin can be found there (this is supported by the fact that there are two Witches of Hemwick). This theory is supported by the removed eyeballs too for the description of the item suggests that the victim could be still alive in the time of the removal.</notes>

<location place="Hemwick Charnel Lane">Hemwick Charnel Lane at the very end of this area.</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Amygdala (アメンドーズ Amendōzu - "Amendoze") is an optional Great One Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>Amygdala is a monstrous entity with a spider-like body, a short tail and a head which is is very similar to a part of the brain called the Amygdaloid, with many bulbous eyes that bulge when it uses its arcane attack. It has six-fingered hands on its seven arms, and reptilian talons on its two legs.</description>

<notes>It's similar to the large enemies who attempt to grab the Hunter with portals, but lighter in color, and lacking tentacles on its head.
Amygdala (plural: Amygdalae) means "Almond" in Latin and "Almond" or "Almond Tree" in Greek (ἀμυγδάλη).
An Amygdala is a bilateral neural structure set deep within the limbic system of the brain. It is thought to be responsible for learning and organizing fear responses. Amygdalectomy - surgical removal of this structure - is associated with reduced capacity to learn memories related to fear and behaving fearfully.
The shape of Amygdala's head (and the heads of the other beings of similar appearance) roughly corresponds with the shape of this region in the brain
In some medieval philosophy the amygdala was regarded as the seat of the soul but also a medium for "animal spirits". Within the amygdala a balance is struck between the rational desires of the soul and the fleshy, animalistic wants of the body.</notes>

<location place="Nightmare Frontier">Nightmare Frontier, at the bottom near the shortcut lift that is guarded by a Silverbeast.</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Celestial Emissary (星界からの使者 Seikai kara no Shisha lit. "Emissary of the Astral world") is a Great One Boss and Chalice Dungeon Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>The Celestial Emissary is initially disguised as one of the numerous Celestial Minions, and its appearance changes very little when it changes phase, other than significant growth in size and eyes glowing cosmic blue.</description>

<notes>While there is very little information on it, this Great One is revealed in the DLC to have been created by experimentation by the Healing Church, who used the orphans they captured as a sort of think tank.
They would have their patients imbibe in water, apparently infested with otherworldly microscopic life that congealed the brain fluid (taken as the generation of the "eyes on the inside"), and listen for the sound of the ocean due to the Great Ones being linked to it by the Church in the past.
This would present itself in the form of a sort of "sticky" sound, which was labeled as the sound of water said to come from the depths of the ocean, and was thought to be the voice of a sort of celestial attendant that guided those with enough brain fluid "eyes" to revelation.
Though most people pass it off as Kin, the boss is confirmed to be a Great One, as the trophy describes it as such.
No Celestial Minions spawn during the fight in Isz Gravestone.
The fight with the Living Failures, who themselves are collapsed and unstable versions of this boss, is fought on the crosswalk above the Lumenflower Gardens.
This location is called the Lumenwood Garden, further linking the two bosses and linking them both to the "lumen plants" they rise from, and possibly explaining the Milkweed Rune's anticlimactic name.
While the method of creating the being is implied through the DLC, there are few theories to explain the origins of this boss, though some of them are listed here.
One prevalent theory is that the being was created from scratch, and as the name implies, exists to serve as a link for the human race to commune with Ebrietas and other otherworldly life.
Another possibility is that this boss was an orphan who became a crossbreed kin from the experiments of the Healing Church, and eventually became a Great One through revelation of the higher planes. In terms of this origin, it is likely that it still serves as a means of communication to Ebrietas.
The fact that it drops the second highest tier Communion Rune, and by the rune's description, the Celestial Emissary could be the source of paleblood for the Church.
To this extent, when added with the nature of the Orphanage and its relation to the Choir (and that you encounter the leader of the School of Mensis and the lead vicar of the Church), one could extrapolate that this being could be the leader of the Orphanage, and by extension the Choir.</notes>

<location place="Cathedral Ward">In the Orphanage, in Upper Cathedral Ward (requires Orphanage Key dropped from enemy).</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Ebrietas, Daughter of the Cosmos (星の娘、エーブリエタース Hoshi no musume, Ēburietāsu lit. "Ebrietas, Daughter of the Stars") is a boss and a "Great One" in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>One of the eldritch Great Ones, Ebrietas is a monstrous creature that resembles a slug with squid-like tentacles emerging from her back. Her face appears split in half and is covered in strange growths that resemble fungus that surround her vulnerable head (only red flesh is seen, so it is possible that she has no real mouth) but, despite being a Kin (most of them have bulging and globular yellow eyes), she has only two oval shaped green eyes. Ebrietas also possesses a set of skeletal wings that grant her limited flight.</description>

<notes>The fact that this being is the conduit between the Church and the Great Ones, coupled with the appellation "daughter" and her appearance, possibly shows that she is the first Celestial Child. Like most of the Kin she has gray blood but is able to spit a red fluid, similar to human blood, that inflicts Frenzy.
When the player finds her she seems to be mourning at the Altar of Despair, which appears to be the corpse of a fallen great one that resembles Rom.
The object of the Healing Church's worship, Ebrietas communes only with the highest members of the Church, guiding them in the ways of Blood Ministration. She is one of the Great Ones who was left behind in the old labyrinth, eventually discovered by the Healing Church. The Healing Church later founded the Choir to protect and study her. She is the only Great One that wants to coexist with humans.
"Ebrietas" is the name of a species of butterflies (Ebrietas), which is fitting as she was massive wings to relocate herself in battle. More interestingly though, is that it is also Latin for "inebriation", or drunkenness. This could imply that Ebrietas is the source of the "Old Blood", harvested by the Healing Church.
Ebrietas can be partially summoned using the Augur of Ebrietas. However, this does not actually do anything to her body, and works after her death. While this is likely an oversight, it could lend credence to the idea that the Great Ones do not die, but are displaced back to their higher dimensional existences until they find a medium to return (the land of Isz) to this world. If that is true, the augur does not summon the boss herself, but her truest form is called upon to generate a representation of her form.
She resembles the Celestial Children. The implication is that they are the result of the Choir trying to give Ebrietas a surrogate child to make her stop mourning.
Her design is reminiscent of the real-world blue angel sea slug.</notes>

<location place="Cathedral Ward">Located in the Altar of Despair in Upper Cathedral Ward.</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Mergo's Wet Nurse (メルゴーの乳母 Merugō no uba lit. "Mergo's Wet Nurse") is a Great One Boss in Bloodborne, and one of the three possible Final Bosses.</name>

<description>Mergo's Wet Nurse is a strange towering creature with six skeletal arms and two black tattered wings. Strangely enough, the appearance of this being appears to be rather Pthumerian, despite its bizarre features, with its long, black, hooded dress and various jewels.</description>

<notes>She has one of two One Third of the Umbilical Cord's in the game that don't require correct actions to be taken at set times. The other being in the Abandoned Workshop.
After Mergo's Wet Nurse dies, the lullaby stops and the baby starts crying. However, using the Tiny Music Box makes the baby laugh before it goes silent.
After defeating her you can also go back the direction you entered, and Queen Yharnam, who was previously sobbing, will bow her head in thanks and vanish.
Mergo's Wet Nurse, along with Moon Presence, are the only two bosses that give the message "Nightmare Slain" instead of the normal "Prey Slaughtered" (or the Japanese message "You Hunted"). However, it could also be argued that the "Nightmare Slain" message doesn't appear until Mergo's crying stops, implying that the Nightmare was Mergo. The DLC increases this number to three with the Orphan of Kos.
The battle is triggered by going near the baby stroller, so it's possible to circle around the whole arena without starting the fight, as long as you stay a certain distance away from the stroller.</notes>

<location place="Nightmare Of Mensis">Wet Nurse's Lunarium</location>
</boss><boss>
<name>Moon Presence (月の魔物 Tsuki no mamono lit. "Moon Demon/Fiend") is an optional final boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>An eldritch being composed of human flesh and bone, with the exception of its head. It's the Great One which created and rules over the Hunter's Dream. Defeating it will result in the "Childhood Beginning's" ending.</description>

<notes>One of the Great Ones in Bloodborne, the Moon Presence controls and manipulates all that resides within the Hunter's Dream. The Moon Presence's origin is largely unknown, but its first known appearance to humanity was to Laurence, who summoned it for unknown reasons. Evidenced by the note located on the upper floor of the Lecture Building, the Moon Presence also has a connection to Paleblood.
"The nameless moon presence beckoned by Laurence and his associates. Paleblood."
Before being encountered by the Hunter, the Moon Presence had bound Gehrman, the First Hunter to the Hunter's Dream, an outlet seemingly used by the Moon Presence to further its own desires, mainly involving the killing of the other Great Ones. Whether or not this has to deal with halting the Scourge of the Beast and the slaughter of other Great Ones is unknown. However, a note found on the upper floor of the Lecture Hall lends legitimacy to the idea that the Moon Presence is actively seeking out and trying to eliminate other Great Ones.
"Hunt the Great Ones, Hunt the Great Ones."
The appearance of Moon Presence resembles Nyarlathotep from various novels written by H.P. Lovecraft.
The Moon Presence, along with Mergo's Wet Nurse, are the only two bosses that give the message "Nightmare Slain" instead of the normal "Prey Slaughtered" (or the Japanese message "You Hunted"). In the DLC, this number increases to three with Orphan of Kos.
The song playing during the first phase of the fight is based on the Nameless Song from Dark Souls.
The Moon Presence may clutch its face right before it begins to thrash. This could indicate a headache or that it's blinding herself.
The Moon Presence may have another name: Flora. the doll has dialogue saying: "O Flora, of the moon, of the dream", and there is no other character named flora that the doll could know of that's related to the moon and the dream. this may also imply that the Moon presence is supposed to be female, as flora is a girl's name.</notes>

<location place="Hunter's_Dream">Hunter's Dream</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Rom, the Vacuous Spider (白痴の蜘蛛ロマ Hakuchi no kumo Roma lit. "Roma, the Idiotic Spider") is a Great One Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>Despite her title, Rom resembles a gigantic pillbug rather than an arachnid. She has a silverfish-like tail and a bulbous body from which vegetation appears to be growing, possibly Coldblood Flowers. Her face resembles a chunk of pumice and is covered in eyes, suggesting its connection to the Great Ones. Rom is initially non-hostile until provoked, at which point will use powerful magic attacks to defend herself.
Rom is accompanied by creatures known as the Children of Rom. They resemble actual spiders but with the same shaped head and appear to have blades for legs. These spiders are possibly either the literal spawn of Rom or were created in order to defend the creature.</description>

<notes>Rom, the Vacuous Spider controls the barrier that prevents normal Yharnamites from seeing the true horrors around them, such as the Lesser Amygdalas crawling around the Cathedral Ward. Rom was once a scholar of Byrgenwerth whom at some point went through metamorphosis into a Kin Great One courtesy of Kos, according to dialogue given by Micolash.
"The Byrgenwerth spider hides all manner of rituals and keeps our lost master from us. A terrible shame. It makes my head shudder uncontrollably." - Note from library area just beyond the Tomb of Oedon.
"The spider hides all manner of rituals, certain to reveal nothing, for true enlightenment need not be shared."  - Note from the second floor of Byrgenwerth.
"Ahh, Kos or some say Kosm... Do you hear our prayers? As you once did for the vacuous Rom, grant us eyes, grant us eyes." - Micolash, Host of the Nightmare.
Rom (白痴の蜘蛛ロマ, Roma, the Idiotic Spider) may have been based on the novel "The Idiot" by Fyodor Dostoevsky.</notes>

<location place="Byrgenwerth">Moonside Lake, accessed from the Lunarium in Byrgenwerth College.</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Undead Giant (死体の巨人 lit. "Corpse Giant") is a Chalice Dungeon Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>The Undead Giant is a massive humanoid being that has weapons for hands. It has large, fleshy lumps on specific parts of its body that, when attacked, will burst, causing massive damage to the giant.</description>

<notes>The face of this miserable being reveals similarities with both Church Giants and Church Servants, suggesting that all these towering creatures belong to the same unholy kind. Its face is the only clue about this connection because the rest of its body is twisted and rotten beyond recognition due to the crude surgery that grafted blades and firearms to its arms.</notes>

<location place="Pthumeru_Labyrinth">Pthumeru Chalice</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Merciless Watcher is a Boss in Bloodborne composed of 3 bosses.  The Watcher Chieftain (守り人の長 Mamoribito no naga lit. "Chief of the Guards") and two Merciless Watcher (Zankokuna mamoribito lit. "Merciless Guard"), one carries a sword and the other one carries a Gun.</name>

<description>Watchers are overweight, pudgy, extremely pale Pthumerians who wield a variety of weapons, ranging from firearms to heated blunt objects and lamps. They will sometimes be covering some areas in cloth. Wrapped with chains for an unseen reason, some watchers have face covering cloth and sometimes take the appearance of a hunting party.</description>

<notes>In some of the Test Chalice Dungeons, the player can encounter sleeping Merciless Watchers. this sleeping animation is unused as none the Merciless Watchers in the retail Chalice Dungeons ever use the sleeping animation.</notes>

<location place="Pthumeru Labyrinth">Pthumeru Chalice</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Watchdog of the Old Lords (旧主の番犬 Kyūshu no banken lit. "Watchdog of the Old Lords")  is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>It is a large, burning, canine creature. It was first revealed in the Chalice Dungeon gameplay video, and currently can only be found within Chalice Dungeons.</description>

<notes>The Watchdog has several eyes inside its skull.
The Watchdog has molars, consistent with both dogs and humans. Its still not determined what it started out as.
It has 5 fingers and 3 toes. In the hind legs the tibia and fibula are exposed.
The Watchdog has a powerful exoskeleton made from bone and unknown parts.
The Watchdog belongs to a group of crocodile like monsters inspired by Berserk's Beast of Darkness - read here.
The defiled version can have up to 28700+ health, making it have the highest hp out of any boss in BloodBorne, and the highest hp out of any boss in the SoulsBorne series.</notes>

<location place="Pthumeru Labyrinth">Chalice Dungeon, third boss of the Pthumerian Labyrinth (Pthumerian Chalice Layer 3)</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Beast-Possessed Soul (獣憑き Kemonotsuki lit. "Possessed Beast") is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>The Beast-possessed Soul is a horned lupine creature capable of using fire elemental attacks, including fireballs, shockwaves, and whips. It can be encountered as a boss in Chalice Dungeons, but one can also be found at the bottom of the Healing Church Workshop.</description>

<notes>The Beast-possessed Soul is the only enemy that can be healed with the Choir Bell.
It is similar in appearance to the Loran Cleric found in Aling Loran Chalice.</notes>

<location place="Pthumeru_Labyrinth">Central Pthumeru Chalice</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Keeper of the Old Lords (旧主の番人 Kyūshu no ban'nin lit. "Watchman of the Old Lords") is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>Granted eternal life by the ones she obeys, the Keeper of the Old Lords protects the slumbering Great Ones.</description>

<notes>Keepers have at least 8 eyes in their head, with pupils and irises. Their eyes resemble those of Amygdala.
Their armor resembles a spider's web and eyes can be found within the gaps. This makes it resemble Amygdala's head.
Eyes can be found within their flames. Similar eyes can be found in the flames of Boom Hammer Hunter.</notes>

<location place="Pthumeru Labyrinth">Central Pthumeru Chalice</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Pthumerian Descendant (トゥメル人の末裔 Toumeru hito no matsuei lit. "Pthumerian Descendant") is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>The Pthumerian Descendant is one of the few surviving members of Pthumerian nobility, the ancient civilization that constructed the labyrinths. The Descendant is a tall, emaciated humanoid and wears tattered robes. Despite its frail appearance, it is incredibly agile and capable of powerful, rapid attacks with the shotel it wields.</description>

<location place="Pthumeru Labyrinth">Central Pthumeru Chalice</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Maneater boar is a Boss and an enemy in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>Maneater Boars are pigs that have been affected by the Beast Plague which has increased their size and given them a taste for human flesh. It has also made them much more aggressive and they will relentlessly pursue anything that enters their territory. </description>

<location place="Hintertomb Chalice">Hintertomb Chalice</location> <!-- Do we have a location for the Hintertomb Chalice? I'm not so sure about the last few labyrinth locations either-->

</boss><boss>
<name>Bloodletting Beast is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>The Bloodletting Beast is a gigantic hulking creature. Its back has been split open and its face is heavily scarred and mutilated, although its still retains a humanoid shape. Even with its colossal size, the beast is capable of stretching its arms to reach opponents and its attacks are incredibly fast.
In the Pthumeru Ihyll Chalice Dungeon, an even more mutilated version of the beast can be encountered. This version lacks a head, although this does not impair its vision, and it is capable of launching parasites out of the wound on its back. When low on health, a gigantic parasite worm will replace its missing head and attempt to bite opponents, inflicting rapid poison.</description>

<notes>His japanese name (獣血の主) means "Host of the Beast Blood".
Because of the skull in The Grand Cathedral, the Headless Bloodletting Beast was once speculated to be Laurence, an apprentice of Master Willem and the founder of the Healing Church. This turns out to be not the case.
The gash on his back looks almost identical to the horns of Manus, Father of the Abyss (dark souls dlc).
The gash is also very similar to the split in the Nightmare Headstone.</notes>

<location place="Pthumeru Labyrinth">Lower Pthumeru Chalice</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Brainsucker is an enemy and can also be found as a Chalice Dungeon boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>The Brainsucker is a humanoid creature dressed in shabby robes, wearing an amulet, and with a pale-blueish appearance with a slender figure, elongated limbs, and a mass of tentacles emerging from its face. Despite its frail appearance, it can run surprisingly fast and attacks with vicious swipes and punches. Often times he is unstaggerable.</description>

<notes>The Brainsucker is capable of a dangerous grab attack that damages the player and drains two of their Insight; a tentacle will emerge from its head, which it will use to impale the Hunter’s skull, in which it will literally begin imbibing the player's brain and draining their knowledge.
There are two variants of the Brainsucker. The hooded version is capable of using magic attacks that paralyze the player and leave them vulnerable to a grab. They are Kin, which means that their blood is gray instead of red and are weak to bolt.</notes>

<location place="Lower Hintertomb Chalice">Lower Hintertomb Chalice</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Forgotten Madman is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>The Forgotten Madman is a former member of the Healing Church that has been driven insane in the Hintertomb Labyrinth. He wears the Madman's attire and wields Ludwig's Holy Blade and Ludwig's Rifle. He is also capable of casting the extremely dangerous A Call Beyond and Augur of Ebrietas, which both deal devastating amounts of Arcane damage.
During the battle, another Hunter named Madman's Escort and wielding a Kirkhammer and Flamesprayer will arrive to support him, turning the until now fair and tough battle into an uneven fight for survival.</description>

<notes>The Madman's Escort will use the clap gesture if you are slain.
The Madman himself uses the conviction gesture if he wins.
Both Madmen have a faint bluish skin color, reminiscent of the local Pthumerians.</notes>

<location>The Forgotten Madman is the boss of Lower Hintertomb Chalice</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Pthumerian Elder is a Chalice Dungeon Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>This Pthumerian royal is a magical expert with a big bag of tricks. He can change his staff into almost any weapon and many of his attacks have magical secondary effects, fireslashes, explosions, summoning flaming spears underneath you. They can appear in any root chalice dungeon and are a good source of Cold Blood Gems</description>

<notes>They have a cane that looks like a darker version of the Threaded Cane. They tap it when teleporting which could be its function.
His transforming weapon could be considered a Pthumerian version of a trick weapon, suggesting Gehrman was not the first to invent this type of weapon.</notes>

<location place="Lower Hintertomb Chalice">Lower Hintertomb Chalice</location> <!-- What should I put for the location of labyrinths? -->

</boss><boss>
<name>Abhorrent Beast is a Chalice Dungeon boss in Bloodborne, and is the true form of the Suspicious Beggar.</name>

<description>A hunched beast with semblance to humans. It has long dark-grey fur and crooked red spikes in its back that surge with electricity, indicating a potential link to the Darkbeasts.</description>

<notes>His lightning coated body suggested him being a Darkbeast, as both him and Paarl are coated with lightning, while the mace Tonitrus is modeled after the Darkbeasts.
The Beast form also resembles the one from Beast's Embrace rune, it could the reason why the Beggar remained sentient even after the transformation.
He actually elongates his arm like rubber in most attacks, making it difficult to guess his range.</notes>

<locationplace = "Ailing Loran Chalice">Ailing Loran Chalice</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Loran Silverbeast is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>The Loran Silverbeast is identical to the regular Silverbeasts found in the Nightmare Frontier and Nightmare of Mensis, although it is significantly stronger.</description>

<location place="Lower Chalice">Lower Loran Chalice</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Yharnam, Pthumerian Queen is a Boss in Bloodborne.</name>

<description>Yharnam was the Queen of the ancient Pthumerian civilization and mother to the child Mergo. She wears a white, bloodstained dress with a veil to conceal her face, although she removes it when the player finds her in the Nightmare of Mensis. Like other Pthumerians, she has black eyes with no pupils and skin resembling a shriveled corpse.
When confronted in the Pthumeru Ihyll Chalice Dungeon, her dress is completely white but becomes bloodier and bloodier as the fight progresses. Her hands are initially chained but she breaks free and wields a dagger in combat. When low on health, she will use her blood to empower her dagger, making it resemble a sword.
Perhaps her most disturbing feature is her pregnancy, the child in her womb (Mergo) constantly cries throughout the battle and is even capable of paralyzing the player with its cries. </description>

<notes>The city of Yharnam was named after her.
Queen Yharnam is first seen after defeating Rom, the Vacuous Spider, gazing up at the red moon.
The red stains on her dress suggests Mergo, her baby, was taken from her before being born. This, along with the fact that she's handcuffed indicates all of this happened against her will. The purpose of this atrocity seems to be making Mergo cry and drawing the Moon close to the world (as seen in the cutscene after defeating Rom) in order to attract and make contact with the Old Ones.
Yharnam, Pthumerian Queen can be seen in the Nightmare of Mensis, standing outside the building where Mergo's Wet Nurse is fought. If the player returns to her after killing the boss she will bow to The Hunter, before disappearing, as a sign of gratitude for freeing or perhaps avenging her baby from the Wet Nurse.</notes>

<location place="Great Pthumeru Ihyll">Great Pthumeru Ihyll Chalice</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Ludwig, The Accursed (醜い獣、ルドウイーク Minikui kemono, Rudouīku lit. "Ludwig, the Unsightly/Hideous Beast") is a Boss in The Old Hunters Expansion for Bloodborne.</name>

<description>He was also the founder of the Healing Church Workshop, and first hunter of the Church. He is also known under his official title; Ludwig, The Holy Blade (聖剣のルドウイーク Seiken no Rudouīku lit. "Ludwig, The Holy Blade"), and adopts this title in the second phase of his fight. </description>

<notes>New dialogue will be triggered upon speaking to him after his defeat while wearing the chest piece from either the Executioner's, White Church, Black Church, Gascoigne's, Tomb Prospector or Choir Sets
Ludwig was named after Ludwig Von Beethoven, the composer of Moonlight Sonata, suggesting Ludwig's affinity with the Moon.
Judging from the way he hold his sword, Ludwig appears to be left-handed.
While most beasts are wolflike in nature, Ludwig is horselike in his deformities, and the only beast to have such a unique appearance.
Much like the Abhorrent Beast the Afflicted Beggar turns into, Ludwig still retains his cognitive functions and the ability to speak.
The Guidance rune was discovered by Ludwig and is directly associated with him. There is also a theme regarding the rallying mechanic and Ludwig himself. Since rallying is the act of recovering health by attacking, shortly after being attacked, this could perhaps be what ultimately fuelled his bloodlust. Even the Holy Moonlight Sword itself possesses high rally potential. It can also even be theorized that since Ludwig calls his sword his true mentor, the sword itself was that which transcribed the Guidance rune unto him.</notes>

<location lamp="The Hunter's Nightmare">The Hunter's Nightmare</location>

<dialogue>
<line>Dialogue after Ludwig reaches half of his health bar:
"Aah, you were at my side, all along.
My true mentor...
My guiding moonlight..."</line>

<line>Dialogue after defeating Ludwig while NOT wearing Church Hunter attire:
"Good hunter, have you seen the thread of light?
Just a hair, a fleeting thing, yet I clung to it, steeped as I was in the stench of blood and beasts.
I never wanted to know, what it really was. Really, I didn't."
(He will then proceed to wail and howl wildly until you kill him, or speak to him while wearing Church Hunter attire.)</line>

<line>Dialogue after defeating Ludwig while wearing Church Hunter attire:
"Good Hunter of the Church,
Have you seen the light?
Are my Church Hunters the honorable spartans I hoped they would be?
(Answer yes)
Ah, good...that is a relief.
To know I did not suffer such denigration for nothing.
Thank you kindly. Now I may sleep in peace.
Even in this darkest of nights, I see...the moonlight..."
(Answer no)
Oh, my.
Just as I feared.
Then a beast-possessed degenerate was I, as my detractors made eminently clear
Does the nightmare never end?!"</line>
</dialogue>

</boss><boss>
<name>Orphan of Kos (ゴースの遺子 Gōsu no ishi lit. "Orphan of Gos") is a Great One Boss in Bloodborne. It was added with The Old Hunters DLC.</name>

<description>The orphan appears to be a Human/Great One offspring of the deceased Kos, the Orphan is a tall, skeletal humanoid. Its mouth is permanently fixed in a rictus grin and it constantly screams throughout the fight. A thin membrane is draped across its back like a cape, this transforms into a pair of wings when the Orphan enters its second form.
"Mercy for the poor wizened child, mercy."</description>

<notes>Once slain, attack the black spirit on top of Kos to get "Nightmare Slain", and complete the DLC.
The Orphan has a connection to Gehrman. After you defeat The Orphan, The Doll will say: "Oh, good hunter. I can hear Gehrman sleeping. On any other night, he'd be restless. But on this night, he sounds so very calm. ...perhaps something has eased his suffering"
The first and second forms are NOT kin, so kin related gems do nothing.
After defeating the Orphan and slaying the black spirit—the "Sweet Child of Kosm"—floating atop the corpse of Kosm, the rain will stop and the moon will disappear.
There are many snail women facing the boss gate in a prayer position.</notes>

<location place="Coast">Coast</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower (時計塔のマリア Tokei-tō no Maria lit. "Maria of the Clocktower") is a Boss in Bloodborne. She was added with The Old Hunters DLC. </name>

<description>According to both her equipment and her weapon, Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower was a citizen of Cainhurst, and is directly related to Queen Annalise. However, she was one of the first hunters to join the nightly hunt, studying under Gehrman, the First Hunter. Despite being a citizen of Cainhurst, who relished in their extravagant uses of blood, she favored her Rakuyo, which required dexterity and skill rather than blood to wield effectively.
At an unknown point in time, Maria forfeited her beloved weapon, tossing it down a well when she could no longer stomach it, and seemingly killed herself. Her consciousness was then pulled into the Hunter's Nightmare.
Gehrman held a curious mania about her, even after she disappeared. The Doll was based on her, down to her facial features, yet, sadly, lacked her personality, leaving Gehrman bitter.</description>

<notes>Killing her triggers additional dialogue with the Plain Doll, further fueling the connection between the two.
She has a special visceral attack animation, in which she will hug the player character before removing her hand from their chest. What triggers it is currently unknown.
Some of the blue lights turn out to be snowflakes. Such snowflakes where also detected during the meteor shower of The Living Failures.
Lady Maria's attire displays a golden salamander
Her Rakuyo can be interpreted as mimicking the hands of the Astral Clock. Some of her stances also seem to imitate the hands of a clock.</notes>

<location place="Astral Clocktower">Astral Clocktower</location>

<dialogue>
<line>A corpse, should be left well alone. Oh, I know very well how the secrets beckon so sweetly. Only an honest death will cure you now. Liberate you from your wild curiosity."</line>
</dialogue>

</boss><boss>
<name>Living Failures (失敗作たち Shippai saku tachi lit. "Failed Creations") is a Boss in Bloodborne. This was added with The Old Hunters DLC.</name>

<description>The Living Failures are massive, slender, alien-like creatures. They are light bluish in color and their arms are curiously elastic. Although having a humanoid stature, they are severely deformed. Their heads are extremely large and misshaped, appearing to fold over itself and connect to its shoulders. It lacks any recognizable facial features. As they cast Arcane attacks, they get two glowing dot eyes, however these float in front of their face and are not physically connected to their head. Their arms are extremely long, almost being able to touch the floor in a standing position. They have large hands, each with 6 fingers. Altogether, it is approximately 2.5 times as taller than the Hunter. They strongly resemble the Celestial Emissary boss found in the Orphanage as well as the Enlarged Head Patients found throughout the Research Hall. </description>

<notes>The theme of Living Failure loosely resembles Seath's theme from King's Field, as well as Mars, Bringer of War by Gustav Holst.
Killing the boss at the very second a Living Failure is spawning can sometimes leave that Failure alive to walk around, attack and perform all of the boss's abilities, even the Meteor Storm. (it will have a set amount of health, though not visible when damaging it)
Killing a Failure while it is casting arcane missiles can leave a black blotch in the sky with no projectiles coming from it.
Their meteors (or comets, as they look like they're made of ice) can produce very tiny snowflake crystals. Extreme close-up required.</notes>

<location place="Research Hall">Research Hall</location>

</boss><boss>
<name>Laurence, The First Vicar (初代教区長ローレンス Shodai kyōku-chō Rōrensu lit. "Laurence, The First Vicar") is a Boss in Bloodborne. He was added with The Old Hunters DLC. </name>

<description>A Cleric Beast, but somehow burning with an inextinguishable flame. Oddly enough, when you first approach it to acquire the Eye Pendant, it has no reaction. Laurence will remain motionless until the player has acquired Laurence's Skull.
Once Laurence has 40% of his health remaining, he tears himself apart and begins crawling towards the player, destroying his legs in the process. He constantly 'bleeds' lava out of his torso and also gains the ability to spew it from his mouth.</description>

<notes>Laurence was the first Cleric Beast ever, as according to Laurence's Skull.
Beast Laurence was destined to reunite with his human skull, but it's unknown if he attacks out of rage or despair or simple mindless aggression.
One of the scholars at Byrgenwerth. The discovery of the old blood inspired Laurence, who believed the healing properties of the old blood were of divine nature, and was the ideal medium to transcend humanity through transfusing it into human bodies. Despite this, Provost Willem held distrust towards the substance, believing the material to be far too dangerous. Given that the Beast rune of Caryll is transcribed by him personally from the sound of a labyrinth beast, it could be that the nature of beasts was already known to Willem, and that he found the risk too high.</notes>

<location place="The Hunter's Nightmare">Hunter's Nightmare</location>
</boss></lore>