<firearm>H@ Cannon

^d" Large prototype firearms fashioned by the workshop heretics, the Powder Kegs. Use of this weapon is equivalent to toting a mounted cannon, complete with its ridiculous weight, staggering kick, and lavish use of Quicksilver Bullets, into battle. Such a monstrosity was doomed from the start, and indeed its development was cut short. Yet, against impossibly gigantic foes, it might be just the thing. "

L@ It's found in the Forbidden Woods inside a big wooden building.
You need to walk into the building behind the enemy who is firing a large stationary cannon. When you proceed into the building, there will be a Viper Pit Mob guarding the area. Stay above and exit on the opposite end of where you entered. Drop down from the ledge onto the exterior roof. Next, kill the Large Huntsman and go up the ladder. Once back inside the building, follow the narrow wooden walkway to the other side and look for another slightly lower hanging walkway. Drop down and circle around until you find a corpse next a destroyed gear; the Cannon is there, where you can pick it up.
As of patch 1.02, it can be obtained without killing any bosses by using the Iosefka Jump to get early access to the Forbidden Woods.

^t" The Cannon has a foldable barrel, which is a reference to the series "Armored Core," notably the WC-GN230 Back Unit Grenade Cannon carried by Nineball.
It's used by a Yahar'Gul Hunter in the Unseen Village.
If you don't own the DLC, the Cannon is the only bloodtinge firearm in the game that doesn't have an actual bloodtinge requirement in order to wield it.
If you do own the DLC, this is no longer the case as the Gatling Gun doesn't have a bloodtinge requirement to wield it as well.

H@ Church Cannon

^d" An oversized weapon used by the Healing Church. A type of cannon that fires with a curved trajectory and creates an explosion upon impact. 
Originally designed for use by brawny men with deteriorated brains, not for just any ordinary hunter.
But the men lacked the wits to effectively operate firearms, and the weapon was quietly ushered into permanent storage."

L@ Found after activating the altar elevator to the Research Hall with the Eye Pendant activate the new elevator to go down. The send the elevator back up, which will reveal an altar with Laurence's Skull. Send the elevator down again via the switch and stand at the altar. This will take you down to a hidden chest. Step back onto the altar to go back.

^t" Other notes go here or in the comments.

H@ Evelyn

^d" Special pistol used by Cainhurst knights. 
The Evelyn uses Quicksilver Bullets, just as any workshop firearm, but the Cainhurst variant relies more on bloodtinge. 
Lovingly named after a woman and graced with an intricate design, Evelyns were adored by Cainhurst knights."

L@ It is found inside a chest in Cainhurst Castle in the library room near the elevator shortcut filled with ghosts (Bound Widow) and barricaded behind tables. You will need to jump from a nearby library staircase to reach the chest.
Sold by the Messengers after joining the Cainhurst Vilebloods at Cainhurst Castle.

^t" Wielded by Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower.

H@ Fist of Gratia

^d" A chunk of iron fitted with finger holes 
The hulking hunter woman Simple Gratia, ever hopeless when handling hunter firearms, preferred to knock the lights out of beasts with this hunk of iron, which incidentally caused heavy stagger. 
Gratia was a fearsome hunter, and to onlookers, her unrelenting pummelling appeared oddly heroic. No wonder this weapon later assumed her name."

L@ In The Hunter's Nightmare, on the body of Gratia inside the last cell on the right, after the Ludwig, the Holy Blade fight.

^t" Other notes go here or in the comments.

H@ Flamesprayer

^d" A special weapon used by certain members of the Healing Church. 
Spits searing flames by using blood-imbued Quicksilver Bullets as a special medium. 
Not the most efficient weapon by any stretch, but sometimes a sea of flame is just what the doctor ordered. 
Besides, the beasts of Yharnam can always use a good cleansing."

L@ Gilbert will grant you this firearm as a gift after you defeat Father Gascoigne (you actually have to trigger the cathedral ward intro cut scene first) and zone in some way (use a lamp to teleport, exit your game, die, etc.). If you have already defeated Vicar Amelia before you attempt to receive it, he will no longer offer it, forcing you to buy it from the Messenger shop instead.
It becomes available for purchase for 8000 Blood Echoes from the Bath Messenger after obtaining the Radiant Sword Hunter Badge.

^t" The Flamesprayer is similar to a real life weapon called a flamethrower.
The design of the Flamesprayer seems like a modified portable version. It does have two tanks that seem to hold flammable liquids and pressurized gas necessary to operate it.
For exactly what purpose Quicksilver Bullets are used for this firearm isn't exactly clear, other than it serves as a special medium of some sort.
Considering that regular fire is already lethal to beasts, it's possible that the Church used Quicksilver Bullets for a religious purpose (in this case, "cleansing").
Used by Church Doctor, Wheelchair Mob and Yahar'Gul Hunter.
Since this item is given as a gift from Gilbert, who later turns into an Old Yharnam Beast, it can be assumed that the Flamesprayer was widely used as a means to burn Old Yharnam down into ashes when the beast infestation took place.
 
H@ Gatling Gun

^d" This is a highly-customised, portable version of the stationary gatling gun operated by the old hunter Djura in Old Yharnam. 
It was the weapon of choice of the youngest of Djura's three companions. 
The Gatling Gun boasts exceptional rapid-firing functionality, but is considered a cumbersome weapon, due to its excessive weight and insatiable consumption of Quicksilver Bullets."

L@ Hunter's Nightmare, cave to the right after getting out of the building that used to be the shortcut to the Cleric Beast in the main game. Gattling Gun Hunter drops the weapon. Amygdalan Arm and a Blood-Starved Beast can be also found here.

^t" Other notes go here or in the comments.

H@ Hunter Blunderbuss

^d" A blunderbuss created at the workshop for the hunters' line of work. Hunter firearms are specially crafted to employ Quicksilver Bullets fused with the wielder's own blood, boosting damage against beasts. The impact of this highly-effective weapon counters beasts' swift movements, and its wide spread is nigh-on guaranteed to hit the mark."

L@ It's available in the Hunter's Dream at the Bath Messengers. First, you must obtain the Saw Hunter Badge in the sewers next to the Giant Boar on a corpse.
At the beginning of the game, it's available as a gift from the Messengers if you choose.

^t" The Hunter Blunderbuss has many similarities to its real life counterpart.
The modern day shotgun derives from the blunderbuss heavily, especially as a close-ranged defensive firearm.
There were many different forms of the blunderbuss, but there were two designs that were used often:
Djura uses a form that borrows designs/mechanisms from a olden day muzzle-loading firearm combined with a short, large caliber barrel, which happens to be the same style the Hunter uses.
Father Gascoigne uses a blunderbuss in the form of a handgun.
It's actually in the design of the Hunter Pistol, but it behaves like the Hunter Blunderbuss when shot.
Prior to release, the Hunter Blunderbuss had the same model as the Pthumerian Watchers.
The lever on the top of the Blunderbuss looks like it may operate a breech block for loading in a shell. 

H@ Hunter Pistol

^d" Pistol made at the workshop, for hunters stalking beasts. Hunter firearms are specially crafted to employ Quicksilver Bullets fused with the wielder's own blood, boosting damage against beasts. The pistol is a quicker draw than the blunderbuss, allowing for speedier responses to attacks."

L@ This is a starting weapon gifted to you by the messengers if you choose.
Otherwise you can buy it from the Messengers for 1600 Blood Echoes after you find the Saw Hunter Badge in the sewers; it is next to the Giant Boar.

^t" At the perfect camera angle, you can see the Quicksilver Bullet in the gun's barrel.
The Hunter Pistol is employed by Eileen The Crow, Henryk, Charred Hunter, Yahar'Gul Hunters and Father Gascoigne.
Father Gascoigne carries a unique Hunter Pistol which fires Blunderbuss shells instead.
According to the concept art, and Gascoigne's shotgun variant, the Hunter Pistol is a "break action" firearm. 

H@ Hunter's Torch

^d" A torch formed by the wrapping a pine resin cloth around the end of a long stick, once used in Old Yharnam. Designed to incinerate beasts and victims touched by the scourge. 
Its fire damage is highly effective against beasts."

L@ It's sold by the Bath Messengers in the Hunter's Dream for 2,000 Blood Echoes after locating it in Old Yharnam.
At the start of Old Yharnam, follow the "lizard" (Scurrying Beast) and it's in the building you land on the roof of. Beware of the cloaked beast hiding nearby the hunter torch's location.

^t" It's currently unknown what exactly is the difference between the Hunter's Torch and the regular torch, other than the former does more damage.
A possible theory is that this torch was modified by the Healing Church to aid the hunters of Old Yharnam in burning the town to ashes.
Lore wise it's speculated that the Healing Church may have had a hand in burning the town, so it would make sense that they would momentarily arm the hunters of the area with more effective torches.
Alternatively, it may have simply been modified by the hunters themselves who burned Old Yharnam down without input from the Healing Church.
This idea seems more likely of the two since the description of the Hunter's Torch doesn't mention the Healing Church at all.

H@ Loch Shield

^d" An artisanal shield crafted with blue glass. 
Originally used to safeguard the leader presiding over a sacred Healing Church ceremony, and later supplied to tomb prospectors, in particular those exploring the labyrinth of Isz. 
The blue is fashioned after a lake, and the shield greatly reduces all forms of non-physical damage. " 

L@ Research Hall: The Loch Shield can be seen right when entering on a platform together with one of the crawling experiments. It's obtained after activating the lever to raise the stairs, then dropping and following the path down.

^t" Loch is the Irish and Scottish gaelic word for "lake". This reinforces the game's overall concept that bodies of water serve as a bulwark against various elements.
This shield, compared to the Wooden Shield, is actually competent and can be useful for some battles.
However, it can still be argued that you can effectively prevent all damage in Bloodborne by simply dodging the attacks and using Rally to survive battles of attrition.
Still, if you're looking to use a shield, either for protection or for thematic reasons, the Loch Shield is a better alternative overall than the Wooden Shield.
*Can also be used as a sled in the Hunter's Dream.

H@ Ludwig's Rifle

^d" A rifle typically used by Healing Church hunters. 
It is said that this rifle was employed by Ludwig, the first hunter of the Church. Its long, heavy barrel makes up in range for what it lacks in reload speed. 
Ludwig's Rifle exhibits several departures from the workshop's design, suggesting that the Church anticipated much larger inhuman beasts."

L@ Can be purchased for 10,000 echoes from the Messengers. Warp to the Cathedral Ward lamp after defeating the Blood-Starved Beast. Proceed through the right-side exit which will now be open. The Radiant Sword Hunter Badge is found in a chest at the top of the tower.

^t" Used by Alfred, Forgotten Madman, Brador and Yahar'gul Hunter in Cathedral Ward.
The Rifle's folding barrel is a reference to WC-GN230 Back Unit Grenade Launchers from Armored Core, which was equipped by Nine-Ball, and lately became the basis of OGOTO Grenate Launcher used by Berlioz.

H@ Piercing Rifle

^d" A rifle engineered by the Oto Workshop, the precursor to the workshop of the heretical Powder Kegs. 
Designed for hunting on narrow streets, this weapon has been optimized to cause perforation wounds, but is unfit for reliably counter attacks."

L@ Purchasable at the messenger bath after acquiring the Firing Hammer Badge.

^t" The weapon can still parry attacks but it is harder to do so.

H@ Repeating Pistol

^d" Repeating pistol typically used by Healing Church hunters. Crafted with mostly metal parts and exhibiting a complex design, the repeating pistol fires two shots at once, making it a ravenous consumer of Quicksilver Bullets. Should be used sparingly compared to its workshop counterpart, as the trump card in one's arsenal."

L@ Can be purchased from the Messengers for 3000 Blood Echoes after obtaining the Sword Hunter Badge.

^t" One of the Church Servants uses this.
Also used by Iosefka and the Bloody Crow of Cainhurst.
This gun's firing mechanics may have been inspired by the wheellock mechanism, which used a wheel and several built-in devices to operate a self-igniting firearm.

H@ Rosmarinus

^d" One of the Church Servants uses this.
Also used by Iosefka and the Bloody Crow of Cainhurst.
This gun's firing mechanics may have been inspired by the wheellock mechanism, which used a wheel and several built-in devices to operate a self-igniting firearm.

L@ It can be bought for 60,000 Blood Echoes from the Messengers after obtaining the Cosmic Eye Watcher Badge.

^t" Rosmarinus is latin for rosemary, which is commonly used as a decorative plant in gardens as pest control. But its more common use is as a spice used for cooking, grown prominently in Mediterranean areas.
Rosemary was known for potentially being able to strengthen the mind's ability to remember things, as well as recall things once forgotten.
It's also used as a method of purification. The Rosmarinus especially seems to follow this theme as it sprays a mist to "purify" its surroundings, as well as make arias be heard.
During the times of the Black Plague, rosemary branches were placed on the floors of homes in an effort to combat the plague. In this sense, use of the Rosmarinus can be seen as fighting the plague of beasts using a rosemary-infused firearm.
Rosemary also has historical association with the Virgin Mary (from Christianity). The description of the Rosmarinus mentions a maiden whom we associate as Queen Yharnam, who in this sense is an allusion to the Virgin Mary.
The Rosmarinus is a symbolic weapon of the Choir. Only the highest ranking members of the Healing Church were allowed to use this particular firearm.
If you look very carefully on the belt of the Choir set, you'll notice there's a small green plant with white flowers attached to it; that particular plant is exactly the same as rosemary in real life.

H@ Torch

^d" A common torch formed by wrapping a pine resin-drenched cloth around the end of a long stick. Hunters choose torches not only because the hunt leads them to the darkest nooks, but also because certain creatures they encounter are possessed of a deathly fear of flame"

L@ t's found next to the Brick Troll who's banging on a locked gate in Central Yharnam. After passing through the town square with the massive crucified beast, you'll come upon an area with a fountain. There you will find the torch and can sneak behind the Brick Troll to open up a visceral attack in order to safely claim your prize.

^t" In real life there are many supernatural beliefs regarding the usage of a torch.
Some believed that a torch could ward off evil spirits/beings, and thus torches in the night were more than a mere means to illuminate a dark path.
Most importantly, it kept people warm at night, so therefore suddenly feeling a chill was a sign that something unnatural was nearby.

H@ Wooden Shield

^d" A crude wooden shield used by the masses who have arisen to join the hunt. 
Hunters do not normally employ shields, ineffectual against the strength of the beasts as they tend to be. 
Shields are nice, but not if they engender passivity."

L@ It's found up the big stairs right after the Cathedral Ward Lantern.
You can also pick it up as a rare drop from early enemies in the game with wooden shields.

^t" For those who are thinking about using this shield, keep in mind the warning issued in this item's description, "Shields are nice, but not if they engender passivity."
Miyazaki has been known to say that the Wooden Shield becomes more important as you continue to play through the game.
This statement is open to interpretation, however, since many believe that the Wooden Shield was purposely designed to be awful, as a reminder to players that to advance in the game they must play aggressively, instead of hiding behind a shield, as was possible in past Souls games.
The Wooden Shield appears to be makeshift, rather than an actual, purpose-built shield.
It's used by a Yahar'Gul Hunter in the Cathedral Ward, specifically the one who wields the Tonitrus.</firearm>