<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<lore>
<!-- Equipment start -->
<equipment>
    <!-- Caryll Rune start -->
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Anti-Clockwise_Metamorphosis">Anti-Clockwise Metamorphosis</runeName>
        <description>
        "A secret symbol left by Caryll, caryllRunesmith of Byrgenwerth. 
        The twisted cross means "metamorphosis."
        
        Rotated anti-clockwise, this caryllRune boosts stamina. The discovery of blood made their dream of evolution
        a reality. Metamorphosis, and the excesses and deviation that followed, was only the beginning..
        </description>
        <locationArea place ="Forbidden Woods">
        (+10%) is found on a corpse behind two celestial mobs in the Forbidden Woods.
        (+15%) is received after talking to Patches the Spider while in his room, no matter which dialogue option is chosen.
        (+20%) is found in a large chest in the first bonus area of the first layer of Lower Ailing Loran Root Chalice. (h3up6y2d)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Boosts Max Stamina
        Versions: +10% / +15% / +20%
        The caryllRunes stack multiplicatively (110% x 115% x 120%)
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this caryllRune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool.
        Dungeon h3up6y2d also contains a Lost Stake Driver on Layer 3 first bonus area.
        </notes>
        <trivia>
        These caryllRunes can easily negate the stamina cost increase from cursed gems 
        (if that is the negative effect you get).
        </trivia>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Arcane_Lake">Arcane Lake</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        This transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices ripples like a watery reflection.
        
        This rune means "Lake", and those branded by it enjoy augmented defense.
        Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark guarding sleep, and an augur of the eldritch Truth.
        Overcome this hindrance, and seek what is yours.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Yahar'gul">
        (+5%) found on a corpse in Yahar'gul, Unseen Village near the skeleton slug shooters, behind one of the burning corpses on the left wall leading down to the boss area.
        (+7%) is found in Byrgenwerth to the left of the lamp, near the tree with the brainsucker.
         (+10%) is found in Isz Root Chalice (random chance)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Increases arcane defense. Arcane damage reduction.
        Versions: +5% / +7% / +10%
        Increases in Arcane defenses are visible in the menu
        Runes stack additively, with a system of diminishing returns.
        When a rune stacks, its effect is reduced by 10% of "what's already there".
        For instance if Arcane defense is already 200, then the increase will be reduced by 20 Arcane defense.
        +10% Arcane defense = +100 Arcane defense, which will become +80 if Arcane defense is already 200.
        
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool.
        Arcane Lake + 10% - Chalice Glyph - ydknsnh4 (Layer 1)
        ydknsnh4 (Layer 1) : Bonus Room before the boss (pre-lantern area also has Deep Sea +300 rune). Also 3 easy bosses leads to a Layer 4 main room with 3 Great One Coldblood. Also a Great Lake 5% (first bonus area 3rd layer) and Ludwig's Lost Holy Blade (Layer 4 pre-boss side area)
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Beast">Beast</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        A transcription of the roar of a labyrinth beast,
        the bearer of the "Beast" rune has accentuated transformation effects.
        
        "Beast" is one of the early Caryll Runes. as well as one of the first to be deemed forbidden.
        The discovery of blood entailed the discovery of undesirable beasts.
        </description>
        <locationArea place=" Healing Church">
        (+20) is dropped by a creature (a weaker variety of Beast-possessed Soul) at the bottom of the Healing Church Workshop tower.
        Starting from the lamp at Cathedral Ward: Enter the door to the right that is unlocked after beating the Blood-Starved Beast, take the elevator up and cross the bridge over to the Healing Church Workshop. Run around a walkway outside the tower and drop down where the ledge is broken to get inside. Descend to the bottom by carefully traversing the wooden platforms inside. At the bottom there is a beast (name unknown) that drops the rune. Can easily be killed with molotov cocktails.
        (+50) is dropped by the Suspicious Beggar on top of the windmill in Forbidden Woods, who you can also send to the Oedon Chapel or Iosefka's Clinic.
        If you engage him initially, you will have to fight him on the rooftop. You can then make him fall to death with the axe charge attack. Luring him to the door you came from also works as he is too big to fit through the door. Allowing you to hit him with longer-range weapons.
        If you invite him back to Oedon Chapel he will start to kill the NPCs there. He is found outside the front entrance, and attacking him here will cause him to transform into a lightning-charged beast (similar to Abhorrent Beast). He drops the rune on death.
        When invited to Iosefka's clinic, a celestial mob will spawn in the clinic who drops the rune. This essentially gives you the rune without having to fight him.
        (+100) is obtained in a Lower Ailing Loran Root Chalice Dungeon. Rotted Lower Loran Root Chalice 2ufsqve2 ; Layer 1 Bonus area before the 1st boss
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Boosts effect from transformation. Temporary boost to transform +20 / +50 / +100
        This Rune increases your Beasthood stat.
        This Rune also decreases fall damage. Each rune has a fixed reduction in percentage, and are not directly tied to beasthood.
        (+20) = 50%, (+50) = 75%, and (+100) = 100% damage reduction. (+20) and (+50) can also be stacked for 87,5% damage reduction.
        </effect>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Beast's_Embrace">Beast's Embrace</runeName>
        <description>
        After the repeated experiments in controlling the scourge of beasts, the gentle "Embrace" rune was discovered.
        
        When its implementation failed, the "Embrace" became a forbidden rune, but this knowledge became a foundation of the Healing Church.
        Those who swear this oath take on a ghastly form and enjoy accentuated transformation effects, especially while wielding a beast weapon.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Laurence, The First Vicar">
        Defeat Laurence, The First Vicar.
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        When equipped, it transforms the player into "The Ghastly Beast."
        This is one of two Covenants that involves transforming the Hunter into a non-human form.
        The other one is the Lumenwood Kin Covenant.
        The Hunter receives a permanent Beasthood meter only when using the Beast Claw, transformed or not.
        It also radically changes how the Hunter behaves, both in movement and when attacking, but only with the Beast Claw. (Backstep &amp; rolling looks quicker - needs testing)
        Most noticeably, the Hunter will howl and screech like a beast when attacking and doing certain movements.
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool.
        The Hunter receives reduced fall damage while the rune is equipped.
        Damage against Beast DOWN effect on cursed blood gem does not affect anyone equipped with the Beast's Embrace.
        In general, gems that specialize against Beasts won't affect a user of the Beast's Embrace.
        </notes>
        <trivia>
        The Beast form loosely resembles the Abhorrent Beast, possibly suggesting the origin of the Afflicted Begger.
        It also resembles a Cleric Beast, similar to Laurence, the first vicar.
        When the Hunter attacks while using the transformed Beast Claws (and you have this rune equipped), if the Hunter stands still suddenly, the idle animation is different than normal.
        The image of the rune resembles a Beast Claw, an indicator of what you will become when you choose to be a part of this Covenant.
        Since gems that effect damage against Beasts won't apply against users of the Beast's Embrace, it might mean the Hunter isn't quite yet a "true" beast.
        This is similar to the citizens of Yharnam who haven't quite become beasts themselves.
        However, it's very clear that the symptoms are progressing, making it possible that lore-wise the Hunter might become similar to the Afflicted Beggar if used for too long.
        </trivia>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Blood_Rapture">Blood Rapture</runeName>
        <description>
        A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds. "Blood Rapture" is the raw euphoria of the warmth of blood.
        
        Restores HP with visceral attacks, one of the darker hunter techniques.
        This rune resonates with servants of the Queen, carrier of the Child of Blood, who yearn for their Queen's blood with little hope of requitement.
        For them, they find solace in "Blood Rapture", that serves as a surrogate for their desires.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Shadow of Yharnam">
        (+200) is dropped by the Shadow of Yharnam  boss.
        (+250) is found on dungeons created with Cursed and Defiled Root Chalice (random chance).
        (+300) is dropped by the second hunter in Eileen The Crow's Questline.
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Visceral attacks restore health. 
        Versions: +200 / +250/ +300
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool.
        This rune is very effective when paired with the Oedon Writhe rune.
        Blood Rapture + 250 - Chalice Glyph: 3zcvutw8, Layer 1, bonus area before boss room
        Blood Rapture + 250 - Chalice Glyph: qs3z8hqa (Layer 3)
        Blood Rapture +300 Chalice Glyph: bdexxpeg (Optional Area at the beginning of layer 2)(edit: this glyph only gave me a +250 rune. Someone confirm?) or dropped by The Bloody Crow
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Clawmark">Clawmark</runeName>
        <description>
        A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
        The "Clawmark" is an impulse to seek the warmth of blood like a beast.
        
        It strengthens visceral attacks, one of the darker hunter techniques.
        Although the difference is subtle, Runesmith Caryll describes the "Beast" as a horrific and unwelcome instinct deep within the hearts of men, while "Clawmark" is an alluring invitation to accept this very nature.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Nightmare Yahar'Gul">
        (+10%) Dropped by the Beast Claw npc in Nightmare Yahar'Gul, Unseen Village after killing Rom, the Vacuous Spider.
        (+20%) Dropped by a beast Gilbert near the Central Yarhnam Lamp after killing Rom, the Vacuous Spider.
        (+30%) Lower Ailing Loran Root Chalice (random chance)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Strengthens Visceral Attacks
        Runes stack multiplicatively (110% x 120% x 130%)
        The Max = (171.6%), if  all Clawmark runes are equiped)
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        The runes stack multiplicatively (tested with the 10% and 20% which gave a 32% increase in damage combined).
        </notes>
        <trivia>
        This rune is based on The Magician Tarot Card.
        </trivia>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Clear_Deep_Sea">Clear Deep Sea</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        This transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices depicts downreaching currents.
        
        This rune means "Deep Sea," and grants augmented resistance.
        Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark guarding sleep, and an augur of the eldritch Truth.
        Overcome this hindrance, and seek what is yours
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Forbidden Woods">
        (+100) Found in Forbidden Woods behind the giant tombstone near the snake heads
        (+200) Found in Nightmare Frontier behind a rock thrower on top of a hill
        (+300) Lower Ailing Loran Root Chalice (random chance)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Increases slow poison resistance.
        Versions: +100 / +200 / +300
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool.
        Clear Deep Sea +300 - Chalice Glyph: 4jgecv28 (Layer 4), rvx9wya7 (Layer 1) First bonus room,ueh7uh88 (Layer 1) First bonus room
        </notes>
        <trivia>
        In the 1.00 version of the game, this Caryll Rune was named "Murky Deep Sea". The reason for the change in name in later patches is unknown.
        </trivia>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Clockwise_Metamorphosis">Clockwise Metamorphosis</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        The twisted cross means "metamorphosis."
        
        Rotated clockwise, this rune boosts HP.
        The discovery of blood made their dream of evolution a reality.
        Metamorphosis, and the excesses and deviation that followed, were only the beginning.
        </description>
        <locationArea place = "Forbidden Woods">
        Forbidden Woods (9 on map).
        Nightmare Frontier in a cave across and to the right of the stone bridge. When facing the giant's back, take a right turn and go down.
        Pthumeru Ihyll Root Chalice (random chance).
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Boosts Max HP (+5%)
        Boosts Max HP (+10%)
        Boosts Max HP (+15%)
        The runes stack multiplicatively (105% x 110% x 115%)
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        Chalice Glyph: 9vb3tzza - Layer 1 pre-boss bonus area. Through the long corridor, then go down one stair and into the mid-level door. Run past the spiders and open the door on the left, the rune is in a big metal chest guarded by many spiders and a madman.
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Communion">Communion</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        Several runes relate to "blood", including "Communion",
        which raises the maximum number of blood vials one may carry.
        
        This rune represents the Healing Church and its ministers.
        Blood ministration is, of course, the pursuit of communion.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Cathedral Ward">
        (+1) Cathedral Ward; in a chest directly through the door on your right. This door only opens after you have killed the Blood-starved Beast.
        (+2) Lecture Building
        (+3) Iosefka's Clinic, in a chest after entering from the secret passage in Forbidden Woods
        (+4) Dropped by Celestial Emissary
        (+5) Pthumeru Ihyll Root Chalice (random chance)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Higher Blood Vial Maximum
        Versions: +1 / +2 / +3 / +4 / +5
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        One of only two runes to have five different versions (the other being Formless Oedon)
        Chalice Glyph: rg56w9w8 (Layer 1 pre-area doorway) Rotted and Foetid Ihyll Chalice. Coffin is guarded by a Merciless Watcher.
        Chalice Glyph: vn6snw4t (Layer 2 pre-area doorway) Foetid, Rotted, Cursed Ihyll Chalice. 
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Corruption">Corruption</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        Several runes contain a nuance of "Blood," including the rune of "Corruption," associated with the oath of the corrupt.
        
        Pledgers to this oath are Cainhurst Vilebloods, hunters of blood who find dregs for their Queen in coldblood, particularly in that of hunters.
        Yet the corrupt are heretics in the eyes of the Church, and thus subject to the wrath of the Executioners
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Cainhurst Castle">
        Secret area after killing Martyr Logarius  at Cainhurst Castle. Wear the Crown of Illusions near the throne to gain access to the hidden room.
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Continuous healing when near death (lower than 12.5% hp).
        Makes enemy Hunters drop Blood Dregs. (NPC or player)
        Wearing this rune will cause all players and enemy hunters to drop Blood Dregs when killed. This also applies when you are summoned, for example being summoned in Old Yharnam while Corruption is equipped could potentially net you two Blood Dregs: one for Djura, and one for the Saw Spear hunter below him. 
        
        While this Oath Rune is equipped, attempting to summon or be summoned by a player using the Radiance rune will cause the summoned player to spawn as a hostile summon. When the hostile summon effect triggers, the player who was summoned will spawn with a faintly purple glow instead of a blue one. This can be hard to notice if you aren't looking for it. Hostile summons occupy a summon slot, reducing the total number of other players the host can summon by one, but do not prevent an invader from also showing up. Hostile summons can attack invaders, normal summons, and the host. It is possible for a very unfortunate host to have two hostile summons, in which case the purple summons will be allied with each other and won't be able to attack each other, but can still attack the host and invader. If this happens, the host player will not be able to summon anyone else until one hostile summon is killed to free up the summon slot.
        </effect>
        <notes>
        Associated covenant: Cainhurst Vilebloods
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        If you summon an Executioner, they will turn into a Purple Adversary
        For relevant lore theories see The Corruption Rune and The Devil. 
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Deep_Sea">Deep Sea</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        This transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices depicts downreaching currents.
        
        This rune means "Deep Sea" and grants augmented resistance. Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark
        guarding sleep, and an augur of the eldritch Truth.
        Overcome this hindrance, and seek what is yours.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Forbidden Woods">
        (+100) Lower Hintertomb Root Chalice - Chalice Glyph: **kfwgav9g** (Layer 3),Treasure in | 2xe8g93y FR Lower Hintertomb L1, bonus area before layer boss | w8zxj7h5 (can't remember which layer, but I just found three runes in this chalice)
        (+200) Forbidden Woods - behind two viper pits in a small cave, near the burning horse.
        (+300) Isz Root Chalice - Chalice Glyph: ydknsnh4 (Layer 1 Pre-lamp). Pre-boss area also has Arcane Lake +10% rune.
        (+300) Cursed Isz Root Chalice (Foetid &amp; Rotten) - Chalice Glyph qqc6wmvz (Layer 3): Bonus Room before the boss (Ebritas). There is also an Arcane Lake Rune in the Bonus Room at Layer 2 before the Boss (Undead Giant).
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Increases frenzy resistance
        Versions: +100 / +200 / +300
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Dissipating_Lake">Dissipating Lake</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        This transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices ripples like a watery reflection.
        
        This rune means "Lake," and those branded by it enjoy augmented defense.
        Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark guarding sleep, and an augur of the eldritch Truth.
        Overcome this hindrance, and seek what is yours.
        </description>
        <locationArea place ="Forbidden Woods">
        (+5%) Forbidden Woods, in a creek under some huge entangled roots near a pig. At the bottom of the final elevator shortcut, go down the path of stairs and take a left turn at the sparkling pond, then follow the creek.
        (+7%) Ailing Loran Root Chalice (random chance)
        (+10%) Lower Ailing Loran Root Chalice (random chance)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Increases Bolt defense. Bolt Damage Reduction
        Versions: +5% / +7% / +10%
        Increases in Bolt defenses are visible in the menu
        Runes stack additively, with a system of diminishing returns.
        When a rune stacks, its effect is reduced by 10% of "what's already there".
        For instance if Bolt defense is already 200, then the increase will be reduced by 20 Bolt defense.
        +10% Bolt defense = +100 Bolt defense, which will become +80 if Bolt defense is already 200.
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        Dissipating Lake + 7% - Chalice Glyph: r4qs4gux (Layer 1, before lamp / first bonus room), fddm4rz7 (layer 3 pre-boss bonus area)
        Dissipating Lake + 10% - Chalice Glyph: kkqmduet (Layer 1, pre-boss bonus room - also contains max strength Fading Lake on Layer 2), 97zvbb6v (Layer 1, pre-boss / second bonus room)
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Eye">Eye</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        A transcription of "Eye," as spoken by left-behind Great Ones.
        
        Allows one to make additional discoveries.
        Eyes symbolize the truth Master Willem sought in his research.
        Disillusioned by the limits of human intellect, Master Willem looked
        to beings from higher planes for guidance, and sought to line his brain with eyes in order to elevate his thoughts.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Nightmare of Mensis">
        (+50) is obtained in Nightmare of Mensis. Spawn at the first lamp and go directly northeast past the yetis and you will find it on a corpse next to the Mergo's Loft: Base Lamp. You can also spawn at the Mergo's Loft: Base Lamp if you have it unlocked and run back towards the yetis and pick it up.
        (+70) is dropped by Ritual Master Willem in Byrgenwerth if killed at any point in the game.
        (+100) is obtained from a Isz Root Chalice (random chance)
        (+100) Can be acquired from a Pthumerian Labyrinth, from a chest in the Pre-Layer 1, Side Dungeon Area.
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Make additional discoveries. Boost Discovery stat.
        Versions: +50 / +70 / +100
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool.
        (+100) Isz Root Chalice along with the use of Foetid, Rotted and Curse Offerings (p3umyztu, layer 1 first bonus room)
        (+100) Isz Root Chalice along with the use of Rotted Offering (ji7y3vu8, layer 1 bonus room before boss)
        (+100) Chalice Glyph: jmph3q6e (Sinister version Layer 1)
        (+100) Chalice Glyph: 42hmimbm (Layer 1 bonus room before boss)
        (+100) Chalice Glyph: rdvjjwhn no bonus offerings (Layer 1 first bonus room immediately to the left)
        Apart from a higher chance of getting rare items, the Eye rune can also be used for more trivial farming, like for Blood Vials. Many mobs will drop more of their standard items, and a clean sweep of Central Yharnam can yield 50+ vials with high discovery.
        Appearance is similar to a variation the Elder Sign from the Cthulhu Mythos.
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Fading_Lake">Fading Lake</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        This transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices ripples like a watery reflection.
        
        This rune means "Lake," and those branded by it enjoy augmented defense.
        Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark guarding sleep, and an augur of the eldritch Truth.
        Overcome this hindrance, and seek what is yours.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Nightmare Frontier">
        (+5%) Nightmare Frontier, slightly past where Chime Maiden is, climb a narrow cliff.
        (+7%) Ailing Loran Root Chalice (random chance)
        (+10%) Lower Ailing Loran Root Chalice (random chance)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Increases Fire defense. Fire DMG Reduction
        Versions: +5% / +7% / +10%
        Increases in Fire defenses are visible in the menu
        Runes stack additively, with a system of diminishing returns.
        When a rune stacks, its effect is reduced by 10% of "what's already there".
        For instance if Fire defense is already 200, then the increase will be reduced by 20 Fire defense.
        +10% Fire defense = +100 Fire defense, which will become +80 if Fire defense is already 200.
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        Fading Lake + 7% - Chalice Glyph: 9d6vhapi (Layer 1: pre-boss loot room; also Uncanny Tonitrus in Layer 1 pre-lamp side area), r4qs4gux (Layer 3), fddm4rz7 (layer 2, pre-boss bonus area)
        Fading Lake + 10% - Chalice Glyph: kkqmduet (Layer 2), 2ufsqve2 (Layer 1, Loot room directly after Chamber of the Seal. Run straight through all the doors)
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Formless_Oedon">Formless Oedon</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        The Great One Oedon, lacking form, exists only in voice, and is symbolized by this rune.
        
        Those who memorize it enjoy a larger supply of Quicksilver Bullets.
        Human or no, the oozing blood is a medium of the highest grade, and the essence of the formless Great One.
        Both Oedon, and his inadvertent worshippers, surreptitiously seek the precious blood.
        </description>
        <locationArea place ="Forbidden Woods">
        (+1) Unlock Iosefka's Clinic as a safe haven and send the young Yharnam girl there. Enter the clinic through the back entrance via the Forbidden Woods and one of the Celestial Mobs will drop this item.
        (+2) Can be obtained in Lower Pthumeru Root Chalice or Sinister Lower Pthumeru Root Chalice (random chance).
        (+3) Dropped by Oedon Chapel Dweller in Cathedral Ward
        (+4) After unlocking the elevator behind the door in Cathedral Ward, use it to go up and exit through the opening in the wall, opposite side of entering.
        (+5) Can be obtained in Pthumeru Ihyll Root Chalice (random chance).
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Higher Quicksilver Bullet max. Max QS bullets held UP.
        Versions: +1, +2, +3, +4, +5
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        One of only two runes to have five different versions (the other being Communion)
        Glyph (+2): vy8hiwxx (First Layer pre-boss side room) Sinister
        Glyph (+2): 868i2ga3 (Third layer pre-boss side room) Fetid &amp; Rotted rites
        Glyph (+5): wikifcsa (First layer) Fetid, Rotted &amp; Cursed rites
        Glyph (+5): 6aima33e (First layer side-room, right after chamber of the seal) Cursed Rite, but no difficult enemies along the way
        Glyph (+5): dm3dhxf5 (Layer 1 before the first lamp) Sinister Pthumeru Ihyll Chalice (Sinister Bell).
        Stacking all three Runes allows one to have up to 4 shots for the Cannon combined with the use of Blood Bullets.
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Great_Deep_Sea">Great Deep Sea</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of ByrgenwertThis transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices depicts downreaching currents.
        
        This rune means "Deep Sea" and grants augmented resistance. Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark
        guarding sleep, and an augur of the eldritch Truth.
        Overcome this hindrance, and seek what is yours.
        </description>
        <locationArea place ="Nightmare Frontier">
        +50 - Lower Hintertomb Root Chalice (random chance)
        +100 - Nightmare Frontier, poison swamp before boss door.
        +150 - Isz Root Chalice (random chance)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Increases all resistance types by +50/+100/+150
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        Great Deep Sea +50 - Chalice Glyph: 2r8ghidm (Layer 2), Lower Hintertomb Glyph: nynpssra (Layer 1) First bonus room / w8zxj7h5 (can't remember which layer, but I just found three runes in this chalice)
        Great Deep Sea +150 - Chalice Glyph: 5xe4d3ny Fetid+Rotted (Layer 1) - First bonus room, u97try9e (Layer 3), wcyfiszj (Layer 3) side passage before boss
        Great Deep Sea +150 - Chalice Glyph: b9agc8f4 , Sinister Isz Gravestone (Layer 1) - Bonus area after opening boss gate.
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Great_Lake">Great Lake</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        This transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices ripples like a watery reflection.
        
        This rune means "Lake", and those branded by it enjoy augmented defense.
        Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark guarding sleep, and an augur of the eldritch Truth.
        Overcome this hindrance, and seek what is yours..
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Upper Catherdral Ward">
        3% - Lower Hintertomb Root Chalice (random chance)
        4% - Upper Cathedral Ward, take a right turn at the top of the stairs above the Lamp.
        5% - Isz Root Chalice (random chance)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Increases all defense types.
        All DMG reduction +3%/ 4%/ 5%
        Increases in defense are visible from the menu
        Runes stack additively, with a system of diminishing returns.
        When a Great Lake rune stacks, its effect is reduced by 5% of "what's already there".
        For instance if Physical defense is already 200, then the increase will be reduced by 10 Physical defense.
        +5% Physical defense = +50 Physical defense, which will become +40 if Physical defense is already 200.
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        Great Lake +3% - Chalice Glyph: 8jv9v6bc (Layer 1 - loot area after locked door)
        Great Lake +3% - Chalice Glyph: qft7c6dw (Layer 2)
        Great Lake +3% - Chalice Glyph: 3j22s3z6 (Layer 3)
        Great Lake +3% - Chalice Glyph: w8zxj7h5 (can't remember which layer, but I just found three runes in this chalice)
        Great Lake +5% - Chalice Glyph: 2tv8fwqa (Layer 1) Fetid+Rotted, bonus dungeon after opening the boss gate
        Great Lake +5% - Chalice Glyph: 8bk4dtfk (Layer 3), Fetid+Rotted (Side Passage before Layer 2 Lantern)
        Great Lake +5% - Chalice Glyph: 7zvhn7dw (Layer 1) Sinister Izs Root Chalice with SInsiter bell rite. 1° bonus room, go up the ladder.
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Guidance">Guidance</runeName>
        <description>
        A Caryll rune discovered by the old hunter Ludwig along with the Holy Moonlight Sword.
        Boosts amount of life recovered by rallying.
        
        When Ludwig closed his eyes, he saw darkness, or perhaps nothingness,
        and that is where he discovered the tiny beings of light.
        Ludwig was certain that these playful dancing sprites offered "guidance"
        They could empty Ludwig of his fears at least in the midst of a hunt.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Research Hall">
        10% Dropped by Carrion Crow on top floors of Research Hall
        Once you raise the stairs and gain access to the very top part of the rafters, there will be a single crow on a ledge, with its back turned to you, close to the windows. It will drop down as you approach, seemingly escaping, to the platform below with the Enlarged Head NPC and two other crows.
        This rune is the only rune in the game that drops more than once in each subsequent playthrough. In each new game, the crow will drop the same rune.
        20% Dropped by Ludwig, The Holy Blade
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Boost rally potential by +10%, +20% and +30%
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool.
        A third guidance rune does exist (30%) in depth 5 root dungeons as listed in the dlc game guide, but no one has managed to discover it as of yet.
        Lore theories can be found under Ebrietas Lore and The Fool.
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Heir">Heir</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        
        The "Heir" sees sentimentality in the warmth of blood, acknowledging this as one of the darker hunter techniques.
        More Blood Echoes gained from visceral attacks.
        Perhaps the "Heir" is a hunter who bears the echoing will of those before him.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Tomb of Oedon">
        Tier 1 - 30% bonus - Encounter with Henryk and Eileen the Crow in Tomb of Oedon. Defeat Henryk together with Eileen the Crow and receive the rune. If Eileen the Crow dies during the encounter you need to defeat the hunter to receive the rune.
        Tier 2 - A stronger version(~40%) of the Rune is found in Yahar'gul, The Unseen Village on a corpse near the second Chime Maiden.
        Tier 3 - Pthumeru Ihyll Root Chalice (random chance)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        More Blood Echoes are gained from visceral attacks.
        Other Versions: There are 3 versions of this rune:
        Tier 1: Enemies killed with visceral attacks grant 30% increased Blood Echoes
        Tier 2: Enemies killed with visceral attacks grant 40% increased Blood Echoes
        Tier 3: Enemies killed with visceral attacks grant 50% increased Blood Echoes
        The above values are estimates, the real values fluctuate quite a bit.
        The lowests value measured for the tier 3 rune is 50% and the highest is 80%
        Values vary by enemy (example: Scourge Beast = 50% but Huntsman = 80%)
        If the tier 3 outcome is (50%), then the above values for tier 1 and tier 2 are correct.
        If the tier 3 outcome is (80%), then the tier 1 and tier 2 values are 56% and 68%
        For tier 3, the values (50%) and (80%) are common, and 25% is rare
        Every rune stacks multiplicatively with other Heir and Moon runes.
        </effect>
        <notes>
        The effects of these runes stack with each other multiplicatively. This means that using Tier 1 (30%) and Tier 2 (40%) together will net an 82% gain to echoes, not 70%.
        It is sufficient to Visceral an enemy once to receive the bonus , the enemy must not necessarily die for the visceral attack but must die in a short space of time.  
        Visceralling a chime maiden appears to also buff the echoes recieved from her summons dying. (confirmation needed)
        The rune works on bosses as well, granted that the boss dies soon after the last visceral. 
        Viscaral two times an enemy in a short space of time double the effects.
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        Heir Tier 3 - Glyph: df235ysm ( Treasure room between Chamber of the Seal lantern and Layer One lantern)
        Heir Tier 3 - Glyph: fp3kttda (First layer, first side room after Seal lamp)
        Heir Tier 3 - Glyph: zziz2qbx (Side area after Layer 3 lamp)
        </notes>
        <trivia>
        You can still receive the bonus blood effect from the runes if the target is (technically) already dead and you did not get a visceral attack off before-hand. But, the killing blow must put them in visceral state (charged R2 from behind or timed shot)
        </trivia>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Hunter">Hunter</runeName>
        <description>
        A Caryll Rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
        This red-smudged rune means "Hunter", and has been adopted by those who have taken the Hunter of Hunters oath.
        
        These watchmen admonish those who have become addled with blood.
        Be they men or beasts, anyone who has threatened the pledgers of the "Hunter" oath surely has an issue with blood.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="NULL">
        Earned by completing the Eileen the Crow questline.
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Increases stamina recovery speed by 10%.
        Members of the hunter covenant may be summoned into a blood-addled hunter's world without ringing the sinister bell as an invader.
        </effect>
        <notes>
        Rune Workshop Tool  is required in order to memorize this rune.
        The guidebook's information on the Hunter rune does not hold up under testing, unfortunately.
        The design of this rune may be a reference to the "Mark of Sacrifice" that is seen in the manga/anime Berserk.
        Relevant lore theories can be found under Moon Presence Lore and Tarot Cards and Bloodborne.
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Impurity">Impurity</runeName>
        <description>
        A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
        This rune, discovered inside the forbidden beast eater, came to symbolize "Impurity," and the oath of The League.
        
        Confederates of The League cooperate with hunters from other worlds, and hunt to discover vermin.
        Vermin writhe within filth, and are the root of man's impurity. Crush all vermin without hesitation.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Forbidden Woods">
        Join The League via its leader Valtr, Forbidden Woods - In the hut to the right of the first lamp, that acts as a shortcut.
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        +2% max HP while co-operating.
        Equipping this rune allies you to The League faction.
        Successful co-op sessions while using this rune will grant a Vermin that can be crushed to rank up in the covenant.
        Equipping the rune also changes the League Oath gesture by placing your left hand onto your chest.
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        </notes>
        <trivia>
        The Caryll Rune Impurity was inspired by "The Lovers" Tarot Card. 
        </trivia>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Lake">Lake</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        This transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices ripples like a watery reflection.
        
        This rune means "Lake", and those branded by it enjoy augmented defense.
        Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark guarding sleep, and an augur of the eldritch Truth.
        Overcome this hindrance, and seek what is yours.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Hemwick Charnel">
        3% - From the lamp at Hemwick Charnel Lane you need to go straight until you reach an iron door. If you didn't open it you need to go open it first. Looking at the iron door you need to go right and follow the path until you come back to the iron door from the other side. Then go straight again until you reach the end of the path and you see some kind of ocean. There will be a corpse on a small ledge with the Lake rune.
        5% - Cursed and Defiled Root Chalice (random chance)
        7% - Pthumeru Ihyll Root Chalice (random chance)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Increases defense. Physical DMG reduction by +3%/5%/7%
        Increases in Physical defense are visible from the menu
        Runes stack additively, with a system of diminishing returns.
        When a rune stacks, its effect is reduced by 10% of "what's already there".
        For instance if Physical defense is already 200, then the increase will be reduced by 20 Physical defense.
        +10% Physical defense = +100 Physical defense, which will become +80 if Physical defense is already 200.
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        Lake + 5% - Chalice Glyph: aii8vj6a (Layer 1 bonus room before boss room
        Lake + 5% - Chalice Glyph: vxnwjixk | Treasure in , F/R/C Cursed Pthumerian Defilement L1, side area before layer boss
        Lake + 5% - Chalice Glyph: brkepzqq (Layer 4)
        Lake + 7% - Chalice Glyph: qtpuhk46 (Layer 1) Before boss room. Also Communion Rune +5 on Layer 2
        Lake + 7% - Chalice Glyph: 7yc94b3m (Layer 2)
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Milkweed">Milkweed</runeName>
        <description>
        A Caryll rune envisioned by Adeline, patient of the Research Hall.
        
        A translation of the inhuman, sticky whispers that reveal the nature of a celestial attendant.
        Those who swear this oath become a Lumenwood that peers towards the sky, feeding phantasms
        in its luscious bed. Phantasms guide us and lead us to further discoveries.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Research Hall">
        Received from Saint Adeline in the Research Hall after finishing her quest line.
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Transforms the player into a celestial Kin form as part of an oath.
        With the Kos Parasite and milkweed rune, the player has unique dodge animations and a slight increase in dodge distance.
        Caryll Rune of the Covenant: Lumenwood Kin
        Small increase in item discovery +10 (Only adds +9 if one has 50 arc and 3 eye runes equipped)
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool.
        Kos Parasite receives an enhanced moveset, but the rune is required to use it effectively.
        Players receive reduced fall damage while rune is equipped.
        Counterpart to the other transformation rune: Beast's Embrace.
        If you go to the Madman NPC figure at the very start of the fishing hamlet with the milkweed rune equipped, he gives you Accursed Brew.
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Moon">Moon</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        A transcription of "moon", as spoken by the Great Ones inhabiting the nightmare.
        
        Gain more Blood Echoes.
        The Great Ones that inhabit the nightmare are sympathetic in spirit, and often answer when called upon.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Hypogean Gaol">
        In Hypogean Gaol between 2 of the Snatchers near your lantern.
        In Mergo's Loft at the bottom of the spiral staircase where you fought Micolash.
        Stand in front of Mother Brain's eye in Nightmare of Mensis and use the "Make Contact" gesture. (Note: it takes around 25-35 seconds for the rune to appear). To get there, start at the Mergo's Loft Middle Lamp and run up the stairs past the crow dogs and ride the single cage elevator down. As you are riding it down, you will see an open window and you must roll-dive through it. Continue along this path past the enemies until you see a single green lever on a narrow walkway to the right of the little hole you drop through (don't drop down the hole). Pull the lever and a cut-scene will play out with Mother Brain falling through a pit. Now you must leave this area and go back to the first area past the spider mini-bosses and the hunter on the bridge. Once you get here, go down the stairs past the dwarves into the big hall will giant pits in the floor. Go past the single giant armored dwarf and you will see a single green elevator cage next to a huge pit in the ground. Climb the elevator all the way down to the black abyss. You can step out and you will not die. You will hear some breathing sounds and you will faintly see an outline of Mother Brain you dropped earlier. Go up to it and perform the "Make Contact" gesture. Stay in this pose for about 30 seconds, after which your hands will move position and you will receive the final and most powerful "Moon" rune. You are free to kill Mother Brain after this and you will receive a Living String (Chalice Dungeon
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Tier 1: Increases Blood Echoes gain from slain enemies by 10%
        Tier 2: Increases Blood Echoes gain from slain enemies by 20%
        Tier 3: Increases Blood Echoes gain from slain enemies by 30%
        The runes stack multiplicatively (110% x 120% x 130%)
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        Also increases the amount of Blood Echoes gained from Bosses
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Oedon_Writhe">Oedon Writhe</runeName>
        <description>
        A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
        "Writhe" sees a subtle mucous in the warmth of blood, and acknowledges visceral attacks as one of the darker hunter techniques.
        
        Visceral attacks restore Quicksilver Bullets.
        Human or not, the oozing blood is a medium of the highest grade, and the essence of the formless Great One.
        Both Oedon, and Oedon's inadvertent worshippers, surreptitiously seek the precious blood.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Hypogean Gaol">
        (+1) is obtained by killing Adella the Nun at Hypogean Gaol or sending her to Oedon's Chapel and killing her there. A second method is to send her to Iosefka's Clinic and collecting the heir rune from a kin.
        (+2) is obtained by killing Iosefka at Iosefka's Clinic, BEFORE the blood moon. (But you lose one third of the umbilical cord)
        (+3) is obtained from a Pthumeru Ihyll Root Chalice (random chance)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Visceral Attacks grant Quicksilver Bullets.
        Versions: +1 / +2 / +3
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool.
        When you manually pick up bullets off of corpses and are already at the maximum capacity any extra are sent to your storage. (standard is 20 bullets max) The rune, Oedon Writhe, does not send extra bullets to your storage. The rune only grants bullets if your current bullet capacity is less than the maximum.
        For those skilled in gun parries, using the Blood Rapture rune as well will let you replenish health, while also replenishing bullets with Oedon Writhe.
        Stacking the two from Adella and Iosefka or having all three runes allows you to replenish up to 3-6 Quicksilver Bullets per Visceral Attack, extremely handy for both Firearm and Arcane build, it even has the potential to recharge the Cannon.
        Chalice Glyph: 27fe7wh7 - Ehik123 on Reddit reports finding the +3 rune in the Fetid and Rotted dungeon. The rune is located in between the dungeon's Chamber of the Seal and the door to Layer 1. This glyph is still active as of December 1, 2016.
        Chalice Glyph: 9vb3tzza (Layer 1 pre-lantern). Pre-boss area also has Clockwise Metamorphosis +15% rune.
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Radiance">Radiance</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        The rune for "Radiance," adopted by the sworn Executioners under Logarius' command.
        
        The executioners despise the impure Vilebloods, and no matter what the circumstances,
        would never cooperate with the bloodthirsty hunters who serve the undead queen, Annalise.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Cathedral Ward">
        If you revisit the statue in Cathedral Ward, outside the entrance to Old Yharnam where you first meet Alfred (after he has killed Annalise), you'll find his inexplicably dead body with the rune.
        This rune can also be attained by killing Alfred after he has killed Annalise
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Increases amount of HP recovered by blood vials.
        Associated with covenant Executioners, which has multiplayer implications.
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool.
        Increases blood vial healing by 2%.
        While this rune is equipped, you will not be able to cooperate with anyone wearing the Corruption rune, regardless of who summoned who. If the player wearing Radiance attempts to summon or is summoned by a player wearing Corruption, the summoned player will be a hostile summon instead of a regular summon. The players must fight each other instead of cooperate. When the hostile summon effect triggers, the player who was summoned will spawn with a faintly purple glow instead of a blue one. This can be hard to notice if you aren't looking for it. Hostile summons occupy a summon slot, reducing the total number of other players the host can summon by one, but do not prevent an invader from also showing up. Hostile summons can attack invaders, normal summons, and the host. It is possible for a very unfortunate host to have two hostile summons, in which case the purple summons will be allied with each other and won't be able to attack each other, but can still attack the host and invader. If this happens, the host player will not be able to summon anyone else until one hostile summon is killed to free up the summon slot.
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <caryllRune>
        <runeName runeList="Stunning_Deep_Sea">Stunning Deep Sea</runeName>
        <description>
        A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth. This transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices depicts downreaching currents.
        
        This rune means "Deep Sea" and grants augmented resistance.Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark guarding sleep, and an augur of the eldritch TruthOvercome this hindrance, and seek what is yours.
        </description>
        <locationArea place="Nightmare Frontier">
        (+100) Lower Hintertomb Root Chalice dungeon. Glyph: qmu2iuhk (layer 1 loot room directly before boss),8jv9v6bc (Layer 1) First bonus room.
        (+200) Nightmare Frontier
        (+300) Lower Ailing Loran Root Chalice dungeon. Glyphs: rie8jhve (Layer 1 Pre-Lamp), s5jj9xs4 (Layer 2 pre-boss)
        </locationArea>
        <effect>
        Increases rapid poison resistance. Adds rapid poison RES +100.
        Increases rapid poison resistance. Adds rapid poison RES +200.
        Increases rapid poison resistance. Adds rapid poison RES +300.
        </effect>
        <notes>
        To memorize this rune, you must have the Rune Workshop Tool
        </notes>
    </caryllRune>
    <!-- Caryll Rune end -->
    <!-- Attire start -->
    <attire>
    </attire>
    <!-- Attire end -->
    <!-- Weapon start -->
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Amygdalan_Arm ">Amygdalan Arm </weaponName>
        
        <description>
        The arm of a small Amygdala Great One. 
        Strictly speaking, the Amygdalan Arm is no trick weapon of any sort, but certain madmen wield them like clubs. 
        Starts as a large, tough blunt weapon formed of bone, but when extended, the hand quivers as if it were still alive.
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="The Hunter's Nightmare">
        The Hunter's Nightmare, cave at the end of the blood river to the right after getting out of the building that used to be the shortcut to the Cleric Beast in the main game. Gatling Gun Hunter dropping the Gatling Gun and a Blood-Starved Beast can be also found here. Arm is near the Blood-Starved Beast at the end of the cave.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The Amygdalan Arm is a Trick Weapon in name only, considering that it is an arm obtained from Amygdala.
        The arm is remarkably small, as even the Lesser Amygdalae are huge. Perhaps it came from a newborn Amygdala.
        The arm could be the inspiration behind the Burial Blade.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Beast_Claw">Beast Claw</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        Beastly weapon wielded by Irreverent Izzy.
        Crafted by chiseling the long bones of an undead darkbeast and fastening them to the weapon. The bones are still alive, and when unleashed, grant its wielder a spurt of beastly power. 
        As flesh is flayed and blood is sprayed, the beast within awakens, and in time, the wielder of this weapon surges with both strength and feverish reverie."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Ailing Loran Chalice">
        Ailing Loran Chalice: Layer 2 treasure room. Room is on the right when exiting the elevator from first layer boss fight, before the second layers lantern.
        Can be bought from messengers for 34000 echoes after acquisition.
        Can be bought from messengers after co-operation with player who has them. This only occurs in Hunter's dream before fight with Gehrman or Moon Presence. It is not needed to complete any Chalice Dungeons. It is unknown if this is glitch or intentional. Was patched by 1.07 or 1.08.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        When this weapon is equipped, your gloves will be replaced by two bone gauntlets. This can allow for the lost art of rapid glove changing if you switch your weapons really fast.
        You can charge the beasthood meter on the first windows (Gilbert) of Central Yharnam
        In the past, there was a rare glitch that allowed a player to obtain this weapon without finding it in the Chalice Dungeons.
        It has since been patched, although it isn't quite known when it was successfully patched.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Beasthunter_Saif">Beasthunter Saif</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        A trick weapon used by the old hunters. 
        A second blade is found inside the curve of the main one. In its initial form, the saif can be wielded like a long curved sword, but when transformed, its blade is contracted, allowing for quick, repeated stabs. 
        Although this trick weapon allows for adaptive combat, it was later replaced by saws and similar weapons that were more effective at disposing of beasts."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="The Hunter's Nightmare">
        The Hunter's Nightmare. After the Blood River, when you pass through the cave with a tick, where you encounter two dogs and a large amount of crows along with an enemy Beast Cutter hunter. Climb the ladder on the left of the pit and instead of going forward, turn to the left and drop down the ledge. There will be a single piece of loot guarded by a Saif Hunter.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The word "saif" is Arabic for "sword."
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Beast_Cutter">Beast Cutter</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        A trick weapon used by Old Hunters. 
        This thick iron cleaver slices through the toughest of beast hides, and when transformed the blade splits into sections, allowing one to lash it in the fashion of a heavy whip. 
        This crude weapon relies on brute force and is regrettably inelegant, suggesting that the hunts of the earliest hunters made for horrific affairs, painted in sanguine black and reds."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Grand Cathedral">
        When walking up the stairs to the nightmare version of the Grand Cathedral, turn left onto a small platform, then roll off and walk down some rough terrain to find the weapon on a corpse.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Reminds many of the Zanpakutō , a fictional segmented sword that can function as a whip. It is an iconic weapon from the Bleach anime.
        The untransformed form of the weapon is a cleaver-like serrated club, and it really looks like the samoan war club "Nifo Oti".
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Blade_Of_Mercy">Blade of mercy</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        A special trick weapon passed down among hunters of hunters. One of the oldest weapons of the workshop. 
        Splits into two when activated. The weapon's warped blades are forged with siderite, a rare mineral of the heavens. Most effective swift attacks,such as after a quick-stepping."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        Can be purchased from the Messengers for 40000 echoes after obtaining the Crow Hunter Badge from Eileen the Crow's quest line.
        Killing Eileen is also a way to get the weapon early in the game.
        While progressing through Eileen's quest, it's possible for her to be killed by Henryk and thus drop the Crow Hunter Badge as a result, although the quest line will end.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The Blade of Mercy was originally named as "Warped Twinblades" during the Alpha test, and it was the tool of choice for the "agile" hunter.
        Both the Burial Blade and Blade of Mercy make mentions of a mineral known as siderite in their descriptions.
        is the real-life alternate name for an iron meteorite, and it seems to be the reason why arcane power has direct scaling with both blade's damage output. Due to its extraterrestrial origins, that may explain why it cannot be buffed by an external source of any sort.
        It loosely resembles the Eleum Loyce from Dark Souls 2, a sword with two blades at the front.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Bloodletter">Bloodletter</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        The demented hunter weapon brandished by Brador, the Healing Church assassin. 
        The Bloodletter assumes its true and terrifying form after it draws upon blood from the inner reaches of one's body and soul. 
        This is the only effective means of expelling tainted blood, or so Brador, isolated in his cell, continued to believe."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Underground Prison">
        Obtain the underground cell inner chamber key.
        Return to the underground prison (from the underground corpse pile lamp, go up the stairs and turn left) and open the door to Brador's cell. His cell is the second on the left behind a flight of downward stairs. Kill Brador to obtain the bloodletter.
        Brador will not be hostile in his cell, but will invade the player right outside his cell.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        [Bloodletting/Phlebotomy is the practice of drawing blood from patients for testing, to cure or prevent illness and disease.]
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Boom_Hammer">Boom Hammer</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        A trick weapon used by the old hunters, and crafted by the workshop heretics, the Powder Kegs. 
        A giant hammer equipped with a miniature furnace. When ignited and fired, it emits a volley of flame that explodes furiously upon impact. 
        Crush the beasts, then burn them - the brute simplicity of the Boom Hammer was favored by hunters with an acute distaste for beasts."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="The Hunter's Nightmare">
        The Hunter's Nightmare. Inside a house that looks out of Central Yharnam, the same that is the shortcut to the cleric beast in the main game, where the 10 quicksilver bullets used to be. Be sure to shoot the explosives around the item (or act fast), as the wheelchair huntsman's corpse conceals a delayed molotov set to trigger when you try to grab the Boom Hammer, potential killing you in a huge blast.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        When the Boomhammer is lit, Beast Patient mobs will back away from the player as if they had a torch equipped. (May need to initiate primed attack first)
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Burial_Blade">Burial Blade</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        Trick weapon wielded by Gehrman, the first hunter." 
        A masterpiece that defined the entire array of weapons crafted at the workshop. Its blade is forged with siderite, said to have fallen from the heavens. 
        Gehrman surely saw the hunt as a dirge of farewell, wishing only that his prey might rest in peace, never again to awaken to another harrowing nightmare. "
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        It can be purchased from the Messengers for 60,000 Blood Echoes after defeating Gehrman, the First Hunter and acquiring the Old Hunter Badge from him.
        To make Gehrman fight you, the "Refuse" option must be selected.
        If one accepts his proposal, the game will outright end there and it will be impossible to obtain this weapon in that playthrough (not including the uncanny/lost forms found in the chalice dungeons).
        Normally, the Burial Blade can only be obtained in NG+ and beyond. However, one can bypass this by using Bold Hunter's Mark, or being killed, during The Moon Presence boss battle.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
         The Burial Blade was the first trick weapon ever created, and it inspired others to develop new trick weapons, usually on the premise of adapting to different combat scenerios.
        Not all weapons adapt to different combat scenerios (e.g. Tonitrus), but the Burial Blade still inspired an entire series of weapons that could "transform" to satisfy different purposes.
        It was created, and exclusively wielded, by Gehrman.
        A Burial Blade can be found above the workshop table in the Hunter's Dream.
        The weapon's description mentions that "Its blade is forged with siderite, said to have fallen from the heavens."
        is the real-life alternate name for an iron meteorite. Due to its extraterrestrial nature, it could be the reason why it has direct scaling with arcane and cannot be tampered by external sources.
        Both the Burial Blade and the Blade of Mercy mentions the use of it in their descriptions.
        Interestingly enough, these two weapons also resemble the talons of Mergo's Wet Nurse.
        The shape of the scythe highly resembles Rurufon's scythe from Shadow Tower Abyss, an early title created by From Software as well as being recurring weapons in Souls series.
        A strange bug on rare occurrences the cape on the hunter may come off, usually in a boss fight you could notice if you dodge back and do an R1 combo the cape disappears. [Note, I haven't seen this happen in a while, it's possible that it may have been fixed, but I'll need confirmation on this]
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Chikage">Chikage</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        Foreign-made weapon wielded by the royal guards who protect Annalise, Queen of the Vilebloods at Cainhurst Castle. 
        When the intricate, rippled engraving that spans the Chikage's blade is imbrued with blood, the sword sings in scarlet hues. 
        However, the rite eats away at the wielder's very essence."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Cainhurst Castle">
        Join the Cainhurst Vilebloods covenant available at Cainhurst Castle, and then purchase from the Messengers for 50,000 Blood Echoes.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The Chikage isn't actually a katana - it is a katana/european sword hybrid. Its short crossguard resembles the one of an early viking sword, or the one of a xiphos (greek sword). The closest european crossguard shape with  this sword is the one of a Karabela (a polish sabre). In other hand, the  hilt and pommel resemble the ones of a longsword (a bit longer, to get easier katana traditional jutsu swings), while the blade shape and the 2-handed fighting style is very similar to a katana. A possible explanation for the origin of this hybrid is that the katana's design was imported to Cainhurst, where some modifications were made to create a sword similar to that commonly used by their knights.
        The Chikage is an allusion to a particular 'breed' of Katanas in the Souls games. While it is similar to both the Hiltless and Chaos Blade from Demon's Souls and Dark Souls respectively, the Chikage bears a stronger resemblance to the Magic Sword "Makoto" (also from Demon's Souls). The Makoto is the only one the bunch to actually DRAIN the user's HP over time, rather than decrease it with each successful swing.
        Chikage (千景) literally means "Thousands Views", however if you separated the word into Chi Kage (血影), it means "Blood Shadow". This could be correlated to the fact that Shadows Of Yharnam wield a similar katana with a slight  crossguard, however without using the bloodtinge.
        The transforming attack has the hunter sheathe the Chikage before unleashing a strike. This is a reference to Iaijutsu, a traditional Japanese sword technique that focuses on quick-drawing. At its finest, Iaijutse allows the warrior to unsheathe and strike at incredible speeds.
        The name seems to be a tribute to Chikage Yamamura (mentioned as a "special thanks" in credits)
        The name may also be a reference to the work "1000 Plateaus" by Giles Deluze and Felix Guattari, a famous philosophical essay about fluidity and functionality, maybe dirrectly tied to the esoteric nature of the weapons function.  
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Church_Pick">Church Pick</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        One of the old trick weapons of the Healing Church, a hunting weapon formed from one of the giant picks that appear in old beast tales. 
        The Church Pick initially serves as a large sword, but when transformed functions as an extended war pick. In spite of its origins, it is a highly practical weapon."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="The Hunter's Nightmare">
        The Hunter's Nightmare: Dropped by a hunter wearing Yahar'Gul set (presumably, this is the summonable Old Hunter Defector Antal) in one of the cells that you open with the Underground Cell Key from the Research Hall. To make this battle simple, attack him through the door with a strong R2 attack, then leave the room. He will lose sight of you and his AI will return to a standstill behind the door. Rinse and repeat until dead.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The Church Pick And The Hunter's Axe both have similar appearance. When transformed, both are wielded as a polearm and have the same de-transformation attack. The only difference apart from the Church Pick having a slightly more complicated mechanism is that the Hunter's Axe is a strength-based weapon.
        A few of its attacks in the transformed mode are very similar to that of the Burial Blade.
        The Church Pick os the weapon of choice of the summonable Old Hunter NPC Defector Antal
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Holy_Moonlight_Sword">Holy Moonlight Sword</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        An arcane sword discovered long ago by Ludwig. 
        When blue moonlight dances around the sword, and it channels the abyssal cosmos, its great blade will hurl a shadowy lightwave. 
        The Holy Moonlight Sword is synonymous with Ludwig, the Holy Blade, but few have ever set eyes on the great blade, and whatever guidance it has to offer, it seems to be of a very private, elusive sort."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="The Hunter's Nightmare">
        The Hunter's Nightmare: Found on the Underground Corpse Pile after the fight against Ludwig, The Holy Blade. Ludwig's head will be lying there and you can:
        Kill the head for the sword.
        Wear a piece of any church attire and talk to the head. When prompted, reply "Yes" and you'll get the sword.
        Wear a piece of any church attire and reply "No", then come back later and Simon the Harrowed will be there and give you the sword.
        NOTE: This weapon is missable. If Lawrence is killed before you obtain it, you will no longer be able to talk to the head or obtain it from Simon.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        It seems to be another reappearance of the Moonlight Greatsword, a recurring item found around FromSoftware's games. Notable examples of such games include the first, second and third Dark Souls games, Demon's Souls, King's Field, Ninja Blade, Enchanted Arms, Armored Core, 3D Dot Game Heroes, and Otogi.
        Lore theories exist under "Ebrietas Lore".
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Hunter_Axe">Hunter Axe</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        One of the trick weapons of the workshop, commonly used on the hunt. Retains the qualities of an axe, but offers a wider palette of attacks by transforming. Boasts a heavy blunt attack, leading to high rally potential. No matter their pasts, beasts are no more than beasts. Some choose this axe to play the part of executioner."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        It's possible to pick this trick weapon as a starting weapon near the beginning of Bloodborne.
        If not chosen, it can instead be purchased from the Messengers after the Hunter has found the Saw Hunter Badge.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        This trick weapon is wielded by Father Gascoigne.
        However, he has a moveset that is different from the Hunter's version.
        He is also capable of using his unique Hunter Pistol even while his Hunter Axe is transformed, which is impossible for the Hunter to do.
        It's also wielded by the Madara's Twin who drops Madara's Whistle when defeated.
        Another hostile hunter NPC wields this trick weapon in the Nightmare Frontier.
        It's been heavily debated by the fanbase whether the transformed mode is a halberd or poleaxe.
        Both forms utilized axe heads with a spear tip at the end (although some poleaxes used hammer heads instead).
        However, neither weapon was known to have extendable handles, which is a special trademark of the Hunter Axe.
        In either case, it's possible this trick weapon was inspired by both weapons and simply incorporated many different designs.
        While wielded in it's transformed mode if the player had a torch equipped in the off-hand beasts afraid of the fire will still recoil in fear of you as if you were brandishing the torch normally (Tested on Beast Patient)
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Kirkhammer">Kirkhammer</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        A trick weapon typically used by Healing Church hunters. On the one side, an easily handled silver sword. On the other, a giant obtuse stone weapon, characterized by a blunt strike and extreme force of impact. The Church takes a heavy-handed, merciless stance toward the plague of beasts, an irony not lost upon the wielders of this most symbolic weapon."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        Can be purchased from the Messengers after acquiring the Sword Hunter Badge.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        A miniature of the Kirkhammer was included as the Pre-Order Bonus for Asian editions of Bloodborne. [See the Bundles page for details]
        A "kirk" is an archaic old english word meaning "church."
        This means the weapon is literately known as the Church Hammer.
        The wording also might be a nod to Nordic culture since the word "Kirk" originated from northern England and Old Norse wording.
        The etched wording on the side of the hammer part has similarities to the Old Norse alphabet.
        However, it also has similarities to the Elder Futhark, one of the oldest forms of the runic alphabet system used by Germanic tribes.
        Similar etchings can be found on gravestones all over Yharnam.
        The sword used for this weapon is very similar to the one used for Ludwig's Holy Blade.
        This suggests that the Healing Church used the method of "interchangeable parts" to efficiently mass produce weapons for their hunters.
        However, the sword used for the Kirkhammer is shorter.
        It's wielded by Alfred, should you choose to be friends with him.
        He uses this weapon as a summon.
        However, he wields the Logarius' Wheel if you find him in Cainhurst Castle under special circumstances.
        When untransformed, with the hammer part on the character's back, some cloth parts (capes etc.) of the armor can either get awkwardly stuck on it or cover it.
        Despite being labeled a 'stone weapon', the etchings, wear, and sound produced when it strikes indicate that the hammer is in fact made of metal.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Kos_Parasite">Kos Parasite</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        When the carcass of Kos washed up on the coast, its insides were teeming with tiny parasites, unlike any found in humans. 
        This atypical weapon can only be clasped tight and swung, but a Kos Parasite is said to stimulate phantasms inhabiting a lumenwood"
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Orphan of Kos">
        Dropped by Orphan of Kos
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The Kos Parasite is perhaps the most interestingly unique weapon in Bloodborne in various ways: It is one of two weapons that can reach it's full potential while using a rune (the other being Beast Claw), the weapon itself is not held, it is purely an arcane weapon, it is the only weapon directly dropped by defeating a boss, it has the highest durability of any weapon at 600 respectively, it is the only weapon to have an A-scaling of any weapon without any upgrades and is the only weapon to have an S-scaling by upgrading it twice.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Logarius's_Wheel">Logarius's Wheel</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        "Weapon wielded by martyr Logarius' band of executioners. 
        Used to slaughter the Vilebloods in Cainhurst. Bathed in pools of their blood, and forever steeped in their ire. 
        Transform to release the power of the wheel and manifest their lingering rage in a show of utter brilliance."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place= "Messengers">
        It can be purchased from the Messengers for 13,000 Blood Echoes after acquiring the Wheel Hunter Badge.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Alfred utilizes the Logarius' Wheel when found in Cainhurst Castle.
        This weapon is yet another reference to Berserk, as they are often made in Miyazaki's previous Souls games.
        "Logarius and his band of executioners" bear many similarities to Mozgus, an insanely devout man who traveled the land torturing heretics along with his disciples.
        The wheel in particular was wielded by one of his six disciples, .
        In Dark Souls, Bonewheel Skeletons are another reference to Mozgus' disciples.
        In real life, although wheels weren't typically wielded as weapons, they were commonly used as torture devices, especially during the Middle Ages.
        Torture wheels were nicknamed "breaking wheels," since victims often times would have their limbs broken during the process.
        They were also known as "catherine wheels."
         It's quite possible that Logarius' Wheel also takes some inspiration in its use as a weapon from the English folklore legend of Tom Hickathrift. Tom was a fabled giant killer who made use of a cartwheel to vanquish the Wisbech Giant (also referred to as an ogre).
        Lore theories can be found under "From Berserk to Bloodborne".
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Ludwig's_Holy_Blade">Ludwig's Holy Blade</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        A trick weapon typically used by Healing Church hunters. It is said that the silver sword was employed by Ludwig, the first hunter of the church. When transformed, it combines with its sheath to form a greatsword. 
        It exhibits several departures from the workshop's design, suggesting that the Church anticipated much larger inhuman beasts."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        Can be purchased for 20,000 echoes from the Messengers after obtaining the Radiant Sword Hunter Badge.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        This trick weapon was wielded by Ludwig, a famous hunter of the Healing Church who designed the blade based on the Holy Moonlight Sword.
        According to the description, Ludwig wielded this sword in combat instead of the Holy Moonlight Sword.
        However, in his boss fight, he wields the Holy Moonlight Sword during a certain part in the fight.
        It is possible that Ludwig wielded the Holy Moonlight Sword and his fellow hunters, inspired by the huge weapon, sought to make replicas. Unable to make a magic sword, a huge metal sheath was the compromise.
        Before the DLC's release, Ludwig's Holy Blade was thought of as From Software's traditional "Moonlight Greatsword" seen throughout various games by the fanbase.
        However, this sword was eventually revealed in the DLC to be a replica of the "true" Moonlight Greatsword in Bloodborne, the Holy Moonlight Sword.
        This isn't the first time Miyazaki used the name of classical music composers in a game.
        A boss from the first "Dark Souls" game, Dragonslayer Ornstein, is named after Leo Ornstein.
        Berlioz from "Armored Core 4" is named after Hector Berlioz.
        The normal form of this weapon is very similar to the sword used for the Kirkhammer.
        However, this sword's normal form has a slightly longer reach when compared to the Kirkhammer's blade.
        The similar nature of these swords suggests that the Healing Church used the method of interchangeable parts to quickly mass produce weapons for their hunters.
        Lore theories exist under Ebrietas Lore.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Rakuyo">Rakuyo</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        Hunter weapon wielded by Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower. 
        A trick sword originated in the same country as the Cainhurst Chikage, only this sword feeds not off blood, but instead demands great dexterity. 
        Lady Maria was fond of this aspect of the Rakuyo, as she frowned upon blood blades, despite being a distant relative of the queen. 
        One day, she abandoned her beloved Rakuyo, casting it into a dark well, when she could stomach it no longer."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Fishing Hamlet">
        Fishing Hamlet. Get to the bottom of the well. Can be reached from the underground tunnels at the end of the area or via a ladder in the well right away. In that area a Shark Giant will wander around. Fighting him makes a second one appear after the first reaches sufficiently low health. The first giant will walk over near the ladder and scream at the ceiling, causing the second one to drop. The second one drops the weapon.
        Fighting the two of them can be difficult and it is a good idea to use the Shaman Bone Blade to make them fight each other and finish off the weaker one. Molotov cocktails are also very effective against them. If neither is available to you, try to kill the one with the anchor first, as it is significantly harder to dodge.
        One easy way to beat them is use of ranged weapon like Simon's Bowblade if you are a bloodtinge build, and the Holy Moonlight Sword if you are an arcane build.
        A Threaded Cane's transformed whip can easily hit the giants from the ledge once they're lured over and begin attacking, but be sure to keep your distance after each hit. Except that there is no way to lure them over the the ledge. No ranged weapon will hit the one standing at the back and the one hanging from the ceiling doesn't drop down until the first one is at 50% health. 
        Unlike other giants in the game, these ones are easy to gun parry for a visceral attack. Keep in mind this will get very tricky after the other one starts fighting, so try to separate them and time your viscerals to get the invincibility at the right moment.
        If your range is inadequate you can use the monocular to angle a throwing knife to be able to hit the shark giant in the back. This way, you can continue from the strategy of killing them on the ledge with a gun/magic without going around. (confirmed as of January 19th, 2019)
        Chaining together backstabs is a very effecient way of dealing with them, if played right you should be able to eliminate the first shark giant before the second reaches you this way. It is extremely difficult to get behind the patrolling Shark Giant without him detecting you. 
        For a video showing an easy way to kill the sharks with a monocular and a throwing knife strategy, check .
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Rakuyo (落葉) literally means "falling leaf".
        The sword of Rakuyo bears resemblance to the "kyū guntō", which was a hybrid of the sabre/katana with a handguard, used during the Russo-Japanese War.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Reiterpallasch">Reiterpallasch</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        Weapon wielded by the Knights of Cainhurst. 
        Combines an elegant knight's sword with the peculiar firearm wielded by the Cainhurst order. 
        The old nobles, long-time imbibers of blood, are no strangers to the sanguine plague, and the disposal of beasts was a discrete task left to their servants, or knights, as they were called for the sake of appearances."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Cainhurst Castle">
        It's found in a chest located in the entrance hall of Cainhurst Castle, where the Bound Widows are first encountered. When you first enter the room from the main entrance, run towards your two o'clock. The chest will be found in a corner.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The Reiterpallasch (from German Reiter "horseback rider" and hungarian pallos [ˈpɒloʃ] "sword") is a 17th century Hungarian straight sword with a typically double edged blade and guarded hilt that was used by Hungarian noble cavalry and later adapted by most western European armies.
        As pointed out in its description, the rifle spear is made "possibly in imitation of a lost Cainhurst weapon" (i.e. this one).
        Wynne D. Fanchon from Armored Core: For Answer; another From Software title, pilots a NEXT named Reiterpallasch.
        Relevant lore theories exist under The Mysteries of Cainhurst Garb and Architecture.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Rifle_Spear">Rifle Spear</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        A trick weapon crafted by the workshop heretics, the Powder Kegs. A prototype weapon serving as a simple firearm and spear, possibly created in imitation of a lost Cainhurst weapon. Lacks any notable functions, saving that it is the only trick weapon with an attached gun. "
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Old Yarnam">
        It can be found inside a hidden building in Old Yharnam. From the area you fight the first NPC Hunter (who wields a saw spear), drop down where the railing is missing in a corner and land on the ledges below. Go into the building and follow the stairs up; eventually you can find it stashed on a corpse tucked away in a hidden nook as you advance.
        Bought from the messengers for 4000 blood echoes after acquiring the Powder Keg Hunter Badge.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        According to the Rifle Spear's description, it was designed as an imitation of "a lost Cainhurst weapon".
        That particular weapon may or may not be the Reiterpallasch.
        It should be noted these two weapons are the only two skill/firearm hybrids whose alternate forms utilize guns.
        The third skill/firearm hybrid weapon in this game is Simon's Bowblade, which transforms from a sword into a bow.
        The Rifle Spear is carried by a Yahar'Gul Hunter in the Cathedral Ward.
        This fight can be tricky because you first encounter a Yahar'Gul Hunter that uses a Tonitrus near the base of the stairs, and if you advance too far towards the houses, the Rifle Spear Yahar'Gul Hunter will join the fight as well.
        He also uses Ludwig's Rifle, meaning he can hit you from a considerable distance with shotgun pellets no matter what mode he uses for the Rifle Spear.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Saw_Cleaver">Saw Cleaver</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        One of the trick weapons of the workshop, commonly used in the hunting business. 
        This saw, effective at drawing the blood of beasts, transforms into a long cleaver that makes use of centrifugal force. 
        The saw, with its set of blood-letting teeth, has become a symbol of the hunt, and only grows in effectiveness the more grotesquely transformed the beast."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        It can be acquired as a gift from the Messengers the first time you visit the Hunter's Dream.
        If you don't select it, you may buy it after acquiring the Saw Hunter Badge in the tunnel with the giant pig (below the bridge to Father Gascoigne.)
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The Saw Cleaver is the Trick Weapon featured on the title screen.
        It was also one of the first weapons to be revealed for this game.
        Overall the mechanisms of this weapon didn't change at all, starting all the way back when Bloodborne was still known as "Project Beast."
        According to the concept art, the Saw Cleaver uses a trigger mechanism to unlock the joint during transformation.
        The design of the Saw Cleaver seems to be inspired by multiple references:
        The transformed cleaver shows a resemblance to LB-66 MOONLIGHT from Armored Core V.
        The Japanese name is written as "nokogiri nata" (ノコギリ鉈) or "saw hatchet". Nokogiri is a traditional Japanese saw that cuts from the pull stroke, as opposed to the more common push stroke.
        In real life, there is a type of cleaver known as a mezzaluna ("half moon") cleaver, known for chopping/mincing up various food products.
        Most of these types of cleavers have handles on both ends.
        However, some use a single handle that stretches across the blade, which was used to chop up herbs usually; the saw cleaver follows this particular model.
        Coincidentally, the Strength/Skill/Arcane scaling at maximum level is "CDC" in their respective order.
        The CDC is an American organization designed to combat and prevent "health threats" of varying natures.
        Since the beast scourge acts like a plague (and is spread due to blood-related reasons), those who wield the Saw Cleaver can be thought of as fighting a dangerous epidemic.
        Henryk uses this weapon when he fights you and Eileen the Crow during her questline, as well as when he is summoned by you when using the Old Hunter Bell.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Saw_Spear">Saw Spear</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        One of the trick weapons of the workshop, commonly used by those who dedicate themselves to the hunt. This saw, effective at drawing the blood of beasts, transforms into a medium-range spear. The saw, with its set of blood-letting teeth, has become a symbol of the hunt, and only grows in effectiveness the more grotesquely transformed the beast."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        Can be bought from the Bath Messengers, after obtaining the Saw Hunter Badge, for 1,000 Blood Echoes.
        Treasure in Central Yharnam Sewer, on the ledge above the dead end with boats. You also need to cut down the corpse hanging from the rafters high above.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Carried by Djura's Ally in Old Yharnam.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Simon's_Bowblade">Simon's Bowblade</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        Choice weapon of Simon, one of the first Healing Church hunters.
        Simon despised firearms, and so the Church workshop had this specially fashioned to his liking. The large curved blade serves as a bow when transformed.
        But aside from a few close friends, Simon was scoffed at for his choice of arms, for who would dare face the beasts with a measly bow?"
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Fishing Hamlet">
        Fishing Hamlet: Found on the body of Simon the Harrowed next to the Lighthouse Hut lantern after answering the first option at the Hunter's Nightmare shortcut and going through his quest-line. Interact with him as he lies on the ground to obtain the weapon.
        You may also kill Simon the Harrowed at The Hunter's Nightmare or Research Hall to obtain the weapon.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Simon's Bowblade is the only weapon to have a S-scaling for two attributes (Skill and Bloodtinge respectively) when fully upgraded
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Stake_Driver">Stake Driver</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        A trick weapon fashioned by the workshop heretics, the Powder Kegs. Favored by the retired hunter Djura. 
        The stake driver, with its queerly complex design, violently drives thick stakes into the flesh of foes. 
        The stake driver allows for high-damage critical attacks, but is difficult to use and leaves its wielder wide open, but none of this should bother a mere Powder Keg."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        Obtain Powder Keg Hunter Badge to unlock for purchase at the Messengers for 8,000 Blood Echoes.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The Stake Driver is exclusively wielded by Djura when he is still hostile towards you.
        His fight is tricky because the area around him is very limited, meaning you can fall to your death if you're not careful.
        Furthermore, the limited space is perfect for his choice of weapon which has a short range.
        This is modeled after the "Pile Bunker," a type of fictional weaponry which launches piston with gunpowder or explosion.
        In the Japanese version of Bloodborne, this weapon is literally called the Pile Hammer (パイルハンマー).
        It bears a striking resemblance to the "Parrying Blade" weapons seen in several "Armored Core" games.
        Has the highest charged attack multiplier out of any other weapon.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Threaded_Cane">Threaded Cane</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        One of the trick weapons of the workshop, commonly used by hunters on their duties. Sufficiently deadly as a rigid bladed cane, but also serves as a whip when its blade is split into many. Concealing the weapon inside the cane and flogging the beasts with the whip is partly an act of ceremony, an attempt to demonstrate to oneself that the bloodlust of the hunt will never encroach upon the soul."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        It can be acquired at the beginning of the game as a gift from the Messengers.
        If not selected, it is later available for purchase from the blood fountain messengers after acquiring the Saw Hunter Badge in the tunnel with the giant pig (below the bridge to Father Gascoigne).
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        This trick weapon is used by Iosefka, Last Scholar Yurie and the Frontier Church Hunter.
        Gehrman carries a generic cane in the Workshop instead of the Threaded Cane.
        This trick weapon is possibly inspired by the sword used by Jean-François de Morangias in the climactic battle of French action-horror film Brotherhood of the Wolf (which bears many other similarities to Bloodborne), or the sword used by a bandit leader in the anime/manga series Claymore. Both these weapons act as a straight, double-edged sword that can transform into a segmented, bladed whip.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Tonitrus">Tonitrus</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        "A unique trick weapon contrived by Archibald, the infamous eccentric of the Healing Church workshop. 
        Striking this peculiar iron morning star flail like a match generates the same blue sparks that blanket a darkbeast. 
        Unfortunately, for reasons untold, the hunters of Archibald's time did not fully take to the device."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        Acquire the Spark Hunter Badge by defeating Darkbeast Paarl  to purchase from Messengers.
        Treasure: Yahar'gul, Unseen Village, at the top end of the road. (guarded by 2 Tainted Dogs and a Snatcher during daytime)
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Tonitrus is a Latin word meaning "thunder."
        The in-game description classifies this trick weapon as a morning star flail, but it's actually modeled in the form of a mace.
        The description of Archibald bears many similarities to Nikola Tesla, a famed inventor in real life who specialized in the field of electricity.
        Nikola Tesla created the Tesla Coil, a device that also bears many similarities to the Tonitrus.
        The Tonitrus also bears similarities with the aspergillum, a device used by the Roman Catholic Church to sprinkle holy water.
        According to the description of the Spark Hunter Badge, Archibald was associated with the Healing Church.
        In this sense, it may have been designed under the themes of "purificiation" and "cleansing" that is associated with many Healing Church trick weapons/tools.
        However, due to Archibald's fascination with Dark Beasts, it's more likely he designed the Tonitrus as a measure to replicate the sparks these creatures could unleash.
        </trivia>
        
    </weapon>
    <weapon>
        <weaponName weaponList="Whirligig_Saw">Whirligig Saw</weaponName>
        
        <description>
        A trick weapon crafted by the workshop heretics, the Powder Kegs, and weapon of choice of the Old Hunter Valtr, the Beast Eater. 
        This weapon pummels beasts in its mace form, but its true strength lies in its attached mechanical saws. 
        These discs, lined with serrated teeth,spin rapidly, thrashing the flesh of beasts into fine shreds."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Nightmare Church">
        From the Nightmare Church go down the stairs and follow the path. Drop down into the pools of blood of follow the path further until you reach the Cannon Executioner. Follow the left wall and turn down the path, the weapon is at the end.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        If you use the L2 buzzsaw attack against Orphan of Kos and hold it in place, it attempts to make an immediate counterattack for each time it gets hit by the whirring blades, only to get interrupted by the next hit. It shrieks every time it attacks, so as a result, it lets loose dozens of overlapping shriek sound effects for as long as you hold it in place.
        A whirligig is defined as a toy that is constantly spinning, such as a top or pinwheel, or as something regarded as hectic and constantly changing.
        Similar to most Powder Keg weapons sharing homage to Armored Core weapons, the Whirligig Saw is based on the Grind Blade.
        </trivia>
    </weapon>
    <!-- Weapon end -->
    <!-- Firearm start -->
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Cannon">Cannon</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        Large prototype firearms fashioned by the workshop heretics, the Powder Kegs. Use of this weapon is equivalent to toting a mounted cannon, complete with its ridiculous weight, staggering kick, and lavish use of Quicksilver Bullets, into battle. Such a monstrosity was doomed from the start, and indeed its development was cut short. Yet, against impossibly gigantic foes, it might be just the thing. "
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Forbidden Woods">
        It's found in the Forbidden Woods inside a big wooden building.
        You need to walk into the building behind the enemy who is firing a large stationary cannon. When you proceed into the building, there will be a Viper Pit Mob guarding the area. Stay above and exit on the opposite end of where you entered. Drop down from the ledge onto the exterior roof. Next, kill the Large Huntsman and go up the ladder. Once back inside the building, follow the narrow wooden walkway to the other side and look for another slightly lower hanging walkway. Drop down and circle around until you find a corpse next a destroyed gear; the Cannon is there, where you can pick it up.
        As of patch 1.02, it can be obtained without killing any bosses by using the Iosefka Jump to get early access to the Forbidden Woods.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The Cannon has a foldable barrel, which is a reference to the series "Armored Core," notably the WC-GN230 Back Unit Grenade Cannon carried by Nineball.
        It's used by a Yahar'Gul Hunter in the Unseen Village.
        If you don't own the DLC, the Cannon is the only bloodtinge firearm in the game that doesn't have an actual bloodtinge requirement in order to wield it.
        If you do own the DLC, this is no longer the case as the Gatling Gun doesn't have a bloodtinge requirement to wield it as well.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Church_Cannon">Church Cannon</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        An oversized weapon used by the Healing Church. A type of cannon that fires with a curved trajectory and creates an explosion upon impact. 
        Originally designed for use by brawny men with deteriorated brains, not for just any ordinary hunter.
        But the men lacked the wits to effectively operate firearms, and the weapon was quietly ushered into permanent storage."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Research Hall">
        Found after activating the altar elevator to the Research Hall with the Eye Pendant activate the new elevator to go down. The send the elevator back up, which will reveal an altar with Laurence's Skull. Send the elevator down again via the switch and stand at the altar. This will take you down to a hidden chest. Step back onto the altar to go back.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Other notes go here or in the comments.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Evelyn">Evelyn</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        Special pistol used by Cainhurst knights. 
        The Evelyn uses Quicksilver Bullets, just as any workshop firearm, but the Cainhurst variant relies more on bloodtinge. 
        Lovingly named after a woman and graced with an intricate design, Evelyns were adored by Cainhurst knights."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Cainhurst Castle">
        It is found inside a chest in Cainhurst Castle in the library room near the elevator shortcut filled with ghosts (Bound Widow) and barricaded behind tables. You will need to jump from a nearby library staircase to reach the chest.
        Sold by the Messengers after joining the Cainhurst Vilebloods at Cainhurst Castle.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Wielded by Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Fist_Of_Gratia">Fist of Gratia</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        A chunk of iron fitted with finger holes 
        The hulking hunter woman Simple Gratia, ever hopeless when handling hunter firearms, preferred to knock the lights out of beasts with this hunk of iron, which incidentally caused heavy stagger. 
        Gratia was a fearsome hunter, and to onlookers, her unrelenting pummelling appeared oddly heroic. No wonder this weapon later assumed her name."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="The Hunter's Nightmare">
        In The Hunter's Nightmare, on the body of Gratia inside the last cell on the right, after the Ludwig, the Holy Blade fight.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Other notes go here or in the comments.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Flamesprayer">Flamesprayer</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        A special weapon used by certain members of the Healing Church. 
        Spits searing flames by using blood-imbued Quicksilver Bullets as a special medium. 
        Not the most efficient weapon by any stretch, but sometimes a sea of flame is just what the doctor ordered. 
        Besides, the beasts of Yharnam can always use a good cleansing."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Blood Echoes">
        Gilbert will grant you this firearm as a gift after you defeat Father Gascoigne (you actually have to trigger the cathedral ward intro cut scene first) and zone in some way (use a lamp to teleport, exit your game, die, etc.). If you have already defeated Vicar Amelia before you attempt to receive it, he will no longer offer it, forcing you to buy it from the Messenger shop instead.
        It becomes available for purchase for 8000 Blood Echoes from the Bath Messenger after obtaining the Radiant Sword Hunter Badge.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The Flamesprayer is similar to a real life weapon called a flamethrower.
        The design of the Flamesprayer seems like a modified portable version. It does have two tanks that seem to hold flammable liquids and pressurized gas necessary to operate it.
        For exactly what purpose Quicksilver Bullets are used for this firearm isn't exactly clear, other than it serves as a special medium of some sort.
        Considering that regular fire is already lethal to beasts, it's possible that the Church used Quicksilver Bullets for a religious purpose (in this case, "cleansing").
        Used by Church Doctor, Wheelchair Mob and Yahar'Gul Hunter.
        Since this item is given as a gift from Gilbert, who later turns into an Old Yharnam Beast, it can be assumed that the Flamesprayer was widely used as a means to burn Old Yharnam down into ashes when the beast infestation took place.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Gatling_Gun">Gatling Gun</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        This is a highly-customised, portable version of the stationary gatling gun operated by the old hunter Djura in Old Yharnam. 
        It was the weapon of choice of the youngest of Djura's three companions. 
        The Gatling Gun boasts exceptional rapid-firing functionality, but is considered a cumbersome weapon, due to its excessive weight and insatiable consumption of Quicksilver Bullets."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="The Hunter's Nightmare">
        Hunter's Nightmare, cave to the right after getting out of the building that used to be the shortcut to the Cleric Beast in the main game. Gattling Gun Hunter drops the weapon. Amygdalan Arm and a Blood-Starved Beast can be also found here.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Other notes go here or in the comments.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Hunter_Blunderbuss">Hunter Blunderbuss</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        A blunderbuss created at the workshop for the hunters' line of work. Hunter firearms are specially crafted to employ Quicksilver Bullets fused with the wielder's own blood, boosting damage against beasts. The impact of this highly-effective weapon counters beasts' swift movements, and its wide spread is nigh-on guaranteed to hit the mark."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        It's available in the Hunter's Dream at the Bath Messengers. First, you must obtain the Saw Hunter Badge in the sewers next to the Giant Boar on a corpse.
        At the beginning of the game, it's available as a gift from the Messengers if you choose.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The Hunter Blunderbuss has many similarities to its real life counterpart.
        The modern day shotgun derives from the blunderbuss heavily, especially as a close-ranged defensive firearm.
        There were many different forms of the blunderbuss, but there were two designs that were used often:
        Djura uses a form that borrows designs/mechanisms from a olden day muzzle-loading firearm combined with a short, large caliber barrel, which happens to be the same style the Hunter uses.
        Father Gascoigne uses a blunderbuss in the form of a handgun.
        It's actually in the design of the Hunter Pistol, but it behaves like the Hunter Blunderbuss when shot.
        Prior to release, the Hunter Blunderbuss had the same model as the Pthumerian Watchers.
        The lever on the top of the Blunderbuss looks like it may operate a breech block for loading in a shell. 
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Hunter_Pistol">Hunter Pistol</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        Pistol made at the workshop, for hunters stalking beasts. Hunter firearms are specially crafted to employ Quicksilver Bullets fused with the wielder's own blood, boosting damage against beasts. The pistol is a quicker draw than the blunderbuss, allowing for speedier responses to attacks."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        This is a starting weapon gifted to you by the messengers if you choose.
        Otherwise you can buy it from the Messengers for 1600 Blood Echoes after you find the Saw Hunter Badge in the sewers; it is next to the Giant Boar.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        At the perfect camera angle, you can see the Quicksilver Bullet in the gun's barrel.
        The Hunter Pistol is employed by Eileen The Crow, Henryk, Charred Hunter, Yahar'Gul Hunters and Father Gascoigne.
        Father Gascoigne carries a unique Hunter Pistol which fires Blunderbuss shells instead.
        According to the concept art, and Gascoigne's shotgun variant, the Hunter Pistol is a "break action" firearm. 
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Hunter's_Torch">Hunter's Torch</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        A torch formed by the wrapping a pine resin cloth around the end of a long stick, once used in Old Yharnam. Designed to incinerate beasts and victims touched by the scourge. 
        Its fire damage is highly effective against beasts."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        It's sold by the Bath Messengers in the Hunter's Dream for 2,000 Blood Echoes after locating it in Old Yharnam.
        At the start of Old Yharnam, follow the "lizard" (Scurrying Beast) and it's in the building you land on the roof of. Beware of the cloaked beast hiding nearby the hunter torch's location.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        It's currently unknown what exactly is the difference between the Hunter's Torch and the regular torch, other than the former does more damage.
        A possible theory is that this torch was modified by the Healing Church to aid the hunters of Old Yharnam in burning the town to ashes.
        Lore wise it's speculated that the Healing Church may have had a hand in burning the town, so it would make sense that they would momentarily arm the hunters of the area with more effective torches.
        Alternatively, it may have simply been modified by the hunters themselves who burned Old Yharnam down without input from the Healing Church.
        This idea seems more likely of the two since the description of the Hunter's Torch doesn't mention the Healing Church at all.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Loch_Shield">Loch Shield</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        An artisanal shield crafted with blue glass. 
        Originally used to safeguard the leader presiding over a sacred Healing Church ceremony, and later supplied to tomb prospectors, in particular those exploring the labyrinth of Isz. 
        The blue is fashioned after a lake, and the shield greatly reduces all forms of non-physical damage. " 
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Research Hall">
        Research Hall: The Loch Shield can be seen right when entering on a platform together with one of the crawling experiments. It's obtained after activating the lever to raise the stairs, then dropping and following the path down.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Loch is the Irish and Scottish gaelic word for "lake". This reinforces the game's overall concept that bodies of water serve as a bulwark against various elements.
        This shield, compared to the Wooden Shield, is actually competent and can be useful for some battles.
        However, it can still be argued that you can effectively prevent all damage in Bloodborne by simply dodging the attacks and using Rally to survive battles of attrition.
        Still, if you're looking to use a shield, either for protection or for thematic reasons, the Loch Shield is a better alternative overall than the Wooden Shield.
        *Can also be used as a sled in the Hunter's Dream.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Ludwig's_Rifle">Ludwig's Rifle</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        A rifle typically used by Healing Church hunters. 
        It is said that this rifle was employed by Ludwig, the first hunter of the Church. Its long, heavy barrel makes up in range for what it lacks in reload speed. 
        Ludwig's Rifle exhibits several departures from the workshop's design, suggesting that the Church anticipated much larger inhuman beasts."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        Can be purchased for 10,000 echoes from the Messengers. Warp to the Cathedral Ward lamp after defeating the Blood-Starved Beast. Proceed through the right-side exit which will now be open. The Radiant Sword Hunter Badge is found in a chest at the top of the tower.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Used by Alfred, Forgotten Madman, Brador and Yahar'gul Hunter in Cathedral Ward.
        The Rifle's folding barrel is a reference to WC-GN230 Back Unit Grenade Launchers from Armored Core, which was equipped by Nine-Ball, and lately became the basis of OGOTO Grenate Launcher used by Berlioz.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Piercing_Rifle">Piercing Rifle</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        A rifle engineered by the Oto Workshop, the precursor to the workshop of the heretical Powder Kegs. 
        Designed for hunting on narrow streets, this weapon has been optimized to cause perforation wounds, but is unfit for reliably counter attacks."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        Purchasable at the messenger bath after acquiring the Firing Hammer Badge.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        The weapon can still parry attacks but it is harder to do so.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Repeating_Pistol">Repeating Pistol</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        Repeating pistol typically used by Healing Church hunters. Crafted with mostly metal parts and exhibiting a complex design, the repeating pistol fires two shots at once, making it a ravenous consumer of Quicksilver Bullets. Should be used sparingly compared to its workshop counterpart, as the trump card in one's arsenal."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        Can be purchased from the Messengers for 3000 Blood Echoes after obtaining the Sword Hunter Badge.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        One of the Church Servants uses this.
        Also used by Iosefka and the Bloody Crow of Cainhurst.
        This gun's firing mechanics may have been inspired by the wheellock mechanism, which used a wheel and several built-in devices to operate a self-igniting firearm.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Rosmarinus">Rosmarinus</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        One of the Church Servants uses this.
        Also used by Iosefka and the Bloody Crow of Cainhurst.
        This gun's firing mechanics may have been inspired by the wheellock mechanism, which used a wheel and several built-in devices to operate a self-igniting firearm.
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Messengers">
        It can be bought for 60,000 Blood Echoes from the Messengers after obtaining the Cosmic Eye Watcher Badge.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        Rosmarinus is latin for rosemary, which is commonly used as a decorative plant in gardens as pest control. But its more common use is as a spice used for cooking, grown prominently in Mediterranean areas.
        Rosemary was known for potentially being able to strengthen the mind's ability to remember things, as well as recall things once forgotten.
        It's also used as a method of purification. The Rosmarinus especially seems to follow this theme as it sprays a mist to "purify" its surroundings, as well as make arias be heard.
        During the times of the Black Plague, rosemary branches were placed on the floors of homes in an effort to combat the plague. In this sense, use of the Rosmarinus can be seen as fighting the plague of beasts using a rosemary-infused firearm.
        Rosemary also has historical association with the Virgin Mary (from Christianity). The description of the Rosmarinus mentions a maiden whom we associate as Queen Yharnam, who in this sense is an allusion to the Virgin Mary.
        The Rosmarinus is a symbolic weapon of the Choir. Only the highest ranking members of the Healing Church were allowed to use this particular firearm.
        If you look very carefully on the belt of the Choir set, you'll notice there's a small green plant with white flowers attached to it; that particular plant is exactly the same as rosemary in real life.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Torch">Torch</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        A common torch formed by wrapping a pine resin-drenched cloth around the end of a long stick. Hunters choose torches not only because the hunt leads them to the darkest nooks, but also because certain creatures they encounter are possessed of a deathly fear of flame"
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Central Yharnam">
        It's found next to the Brick Troll who's banging on a locked gate in Central Yharnam. After passing through the town square with the massive crucified beast, you'll come upon an area with a fountain. There you will find the torch and can sneak behind the Brick Troll to open up a visceral attack in order to safely claim your prize.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        In real life there are many supernatural beliefs regarding the usage of a torch.
        Some believed that a torch could ward off evil spirits/beings, and thus torches in the night were more than a mere means to illuminate a dark path.
        Most importantly, it kept people warm at night, so therefore suddenly feeling a chill was a sign that something unnatural was nearby.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <firearm>
        <firearmName firearmList="Wooden_Shield">Wooden Shield</firearmName>
        
        <description>
        A crude wooden shield used by the masses who have arisen to join the hunt. 
        Hunters do not normally employ shields, ineffectual against the strength of the beasts as they tend to be. 
        Shields are nice, but not if they engender passivity."
        </description>
        
        <locationArea place="Cathedral Ward">
        It's found up the big stairs right after the Cathedral Ward Lantern.
        You can also pick it up as a rare drop from early enemies in the game with wooden shields.
        </locationArea>
        
        <trivia>
        For those who are thinking about using this shield, keep in mind the warning issued in this item's description, "Shields are nice, but not if they engender passivity."
        Miyazaki has been known to say that the Wooden Shield becomes more important as you continue to play through the game.
        This statement is open to interpretation, however, since many believe that the Wooden Shield was purposely designed to be awful, as a reminder to players that to advance in the game they must play aggressively, instead of hiding behind a shield, as was possible in past Souls games.
        The Wooden Shield appears to be makeshift, rather than an actual, purpose-built shield.
        It's used by a Yahar'Gul Hunter in the Cathedral Ward, specifically the one who wields the Tonitrus.
        </trivia>
        
    </firearm>
    <!-- Firearm end -->
    <!-- Item start -->
    <item>
        
    </item>
    <!-- Item end -->
</equipment>
<!-- Equipment end -->
<!-- Area start -->
<area>
    
</area>
<!-- Area end -->
<!-- Npc start -->
<npc>
    
</npc>
<!-- Npc end -->
<!-- Boss start -->
<boss>
    
</boss>
<!-- Boss end -->
</lore>